In this video, I'm going to share with
you the ultimate guide to ChatGpt 5.6
and the updated Chat GPT app that
combines all of OpenAI's offerings into
one place. I'm going to walk you through
the features, the howto, and then get
into some detailed prompts of some of
the crazy things you can do with this
app and model. Let's get into it. Oh, by
the way, before we get into it, this
video is sponsored by OpenAI, but I owe
it to you to be honest and truthful with
everything I say. I always do that with
all of my videos. So, everything in this
video is truthful and my experience and
also me showing some other things that
other people have done with it, but I do
appreciate OpenAI for agreeing to
sponsor this one. All right, let's get
into the good stuff. Let's start with a
bit of a tour of the new chat GPT app
because this new app is essentially
OpenAI taking ChatGpt, taking Codeex,
taking their browser app and taking
their new chat GBT work platform and
mashing them all together into one
products. You don't need to switch
between tools all the time. So, we have
ChatGpt Codeex. You get to it by
clicking on the little drop down in the
top left here. And this is the portion
of the platform that's for developers.
This is where you're going to be writing
code, prompting it to write code,
reviewing diffs, fixing bugs, exploring
code, that sort of thing. And then you
have the new chat GPT work section of
the app. This is the section that's for
like regular people that just want to
give this tool actions to go do on their
behalf. This is where you're going to
have it be like your assistant and have
it connect to your various tools and
just go do things. I'll get to some
examples of what that looks like in just
a minute here, but let's continue the
tour for a second because there's some
other really cool things they've added
to this platform. You've got sites over
here. This is OpenAI making it so you
don't need a million different tools to
get something online. You don't have to
deal with web hosting or back-end
databases or CDNs or anything like that.
When you're building something like a
website or an app or a game, you can
actually tell this new app, send it to
sites and it will be live and online and
you can share it with anybody. Anybody
can access it. It is all just hosted for
you now with this new sites feature
inside of chat GPT. Now, there's also a
browser built in. If I toggle our side
panel here, you can see there's a link
to a browser. If I click into this, I
could open this window wider and we have
a browser where you can go anywhere. For
example, futuretools.io.
One thing that's really cool about this
browser is you've got this annotate
feature. So let's say you're working on
a website inside of the new chat GPT
app, you can tell it exactly which
section you need help with. Like let's
say I want to edit this brain here. I
could select this section and annotate
it and say let's add more green to this.
And you can see over in my chat window
here, it added the one annotation that I
just gave it. If I was actually working
with the code for this website, it would
know exactly what I'm talking about.
out. I don't have to give it more
context because it knows which part of
the screen and what I want it to do. You
can also import your cookies and
passwords from your other browser if you
want. So, if you're already using
something like Chrome, you can pull them
all over and it will be able to log into
those websites on your behalf, which is
really cool, which I'll show you more
examples of that in a few minutes here,
too. But let's continue the tour here
because there's still more to show off.
You can create scheduled tasks. So,
let's say you have a prompt that you
just want this prompt to run every
single day or every single hour. You can
create these scheduled tasks that will
just run on autopilot. Let's say you
want it to do something like clean your
downloads folder. You can have it
automatically clean your downloads
folder for you and organize things into
folders at a regular cadence once a day.
You can have it create daily briefs
where it'll read your calendar, your
unread emails, things like that, and
give you that brief. You could do weekly
reviews or follow-up monitor where it
will watch your emails and let you know
when you need to follow up with
somebody. This comes in really handy.
And I have a whole bunch of scheduled
tasks as you can see later in the video.
Those tasks that you're seeing on the
screen will make more sense of what
they're actually doing. You've also got
this chat up here. This is for when you
just want to ask ChatGpt a question. So,
if I click this chat, it'll open up this
sidebar chat. And this is really handy
because you can have this sidebar chat
open while you're coding something else.
Let's say I'm working on future tools
over here and it's coding up some new
feature for me. I can be working on the
code right here while having a separate
side chat and asking a question to chat
GPT over here. And of course, it
connects to like every app you're going
to use. You can see what I have it
connected to right now. If I show you my
full list, you can see I've got it
connected to the full suite of Google
Docs. I've got it connected to GitHub,
Google Drive, Gmail, Slack, Google
Calendar, Canva, Figma, Superbase,
Verscell, Granola, To-Doist, and a
handful of other like little skills and
plugins that I've installed. But because
it's connected to so much, and because I
allow it to actually use my computer,
and because I actually gave it access to
use the browser, it can like do anything
on my computer that I could do almost.
It also knows everything about me and my
business because it sees my Slack
conversations. It sees my Gmail
conversations. It sees my to-do list. It
sees all of my previous chats I've had
with it. It sees all of my meetings that
I have on Granola. So, it knows
everything that's going on in my
business at any time, which makes it
really, really easy to ask it questions
and get advice on my business because
it's got so much information about it.
And again, you can allow it to use your
computer as well. So, if you go into
settings and computer use, you can allow
it to use any app for you. You can allow
it to use Google Chrome. You can also
let it control the internal browser,
which is really cool when you want it to
go and like scan Twitter or Instagram or
something like that for you. All right,
I think that's pretty much the tour. I
could keep on sharing features, but
let's actually get our hands on it and
dive in and show you what it can really
do. So, I'm going to show off a bunch of
prompts here. Some of them are going to
be prompts that I gave the model. Some
are going to be prompts that I found
that the community used and created some
really cool stuff with it. One thing
you're going to notice when using the
new chat GPT app is that sometimes it's
going to take a bit longer to get the
outputs, especially on some of these
more complex and like intense projects
I'm going to show you. So, what I'm
going to do is I'm going to show you the
prompt on the screen and then we'll look
at and talk about the output. I'm not
actually prompting these in real time as
I'm recording this. Not because I don't
know what the outcome's going to be, but
because some of these I would have given
it a prompt and it might have taken an
hour to complete. Some of them it might
have taken only 2 or 3 minutes to
complete, but because of that
uncertainty around the amount of time it
took to get these responses, I just went
ahead and pre-prompted them all. When
you're using this new chat GPT app, what
you'll notice is that sometimes these
prompts take a little bit longer to give
you a response because your first prompt
is sending off little workers to go and
do all of the other little prompts for
you and do a bunch of little tasks. So
again, because of that, some of these
take a little bit longer to generate the
response and give you the output you're
looking for, but the results are
typically something way better than
we've seen from any previous AI models.
All right, let's check out some of these
prompts. So, one of the coolest things
about the new app is the chat GPT work
mode that acts kind of like a personal
assistant, and I've been really, really
impressed with what it can do. So, I
actually created a project that's pinned
to the top of my sidebar here. It's
actually the topmost pinned project cuz
I find myself using it the most, but I
called it my personal assistant project.
Now, when I created this project, I gave
it a couple prompts so that it becomes a
better personal assistant from here on
out. The first prompt I gave it was to
create a skill for itself that gives it
access to everything. So again, I'm not
going to read this whole prompt, but
here's what I essentially said. I want
you to create a skill where every time I
give a prompt inside of the personal
assistant project here in chat GPT, you
automatically have access to everything.
You could see my Gmail, Calendar, Slack,
Granola, Google Drive, Second Brain
Files, journals, all of my other
prompts, projects and chats, my
memories, what's in my control tower,
future tools, my Twitter and Instagram
accounts via the browser, my YouTube
channel, literally everything. And then
I essentially told it that when I'm
prompting the personal assistant, call
on this skill. So my personal assistant
knows it can access all of that. I also
gave it instructions that this should be
read only. You don't have access to
write to any of those things, but you
can read from any of those things. So,
you can see it created a full context
skill. So, it'll proactively retrieve
relevant context while defaulting to
read only. It created a projectwide
trigger, so requires the skill for every
new prompt in this personal assistant
project here. It's got an evolving
source map. So, the source map is
everything I told it it can access, but
also it evolves. So if I add new plugins
or new tools, they get added to the
source map as well. So now I've got this
personal assistant project that knows
literally everything about me that I do
on my computer. So then the second
prompt that I give to sort of train my
personal assistant here is this analyze
email and chat voice. And this is so
that when I have it write emails on my
behalf or Slack messages on my behalf,
it knows how to write like me. Now, I
don't give it access to write and then
send on my behalf. But I do allow it to
write for me, save things as a draft, so
I can review them, modify them a little
bit, and then click send. But here's the
prompt that I give. Essentially just
saying analyze the messages I've
authored in my sent email and work chat
over the last 12 months. Exclude
forwarded material and copied text. And
then it created an email voice profile
and a work chat voice profile. And so
now when I ask it to draft emails for me
or draft a Slack message for me, it has
a voice profile to follow that
theoretically will sound fairly close to
me. It's still not perfect. You're still
probably going to want to reword some
stuff and take out some of the chat GPT
isms, but it gets pretty close. Now,
once you've got those few things dialed
in with your personal assistant, you can
do some pretty cool stuff. So, I'm
actually working on a book right now
that's going to be through a traditional
publisher. I can't talk too much about
it, but I had my personal assistant
create a book on one pager for me. And
here's the thing, since it has access to
my previous chats, I can go to a
previous chat, rightclick on it, and
then say copy session ID. And then I
could paste those session IDs in, and my
assistant will read those past chats
specifically. The current working title
of the book is The New Leverage. That's
probably not going to be the vital
title. That's just kind of the code name
for it now. But I gave it this prompt.
I've been planning a book. I've talked
about it in this session, this session,
and this session. Help me put together a
one-pager or one sheet for this book. I
need a one-page writeup that sums it all
up and pitches the idea to people. And
because it saw my past discussions and
knows everything I'm talking about with
the book, it created a one sheet for
that book. Now, I'm blurring most of it
because I'm still dialing it in and
working with people on it, but uh
there's a little teaser right there that
you can see. The beautiful part about
this was I didn't have to give it a ton
of extra context cuz I've already had
multiple chats about my book with Chad
GPT. I just pointed my assistant back to
them and said, "We've already talked
about this. Go write me the one pager."
You can have it help build a slide deck
for you. This is something I actually
did recently. I'm actually doing a
webinar with Teachable on July 22nd
called Deciding What to Automate with AI
in Your Personal and Work Life. I had
the outline of the presentation. I knew
everything I was going to talk about,
but I really really don't like making
slide decks. It's like one of my least
favorite things ever. So, I gave the
outline to the chat GPT app along with a
brief that Teachable wrote up for me so
it knew additional context around it and
basically said, "Make the slide deck for
me." And it did. And it looks pretty
decent as well. I'm not going to show
the entire presentation. I'll save that
for when I actually do the webinar, but
it went and grabbed screenshots from my
actual website, put text on the screen,
knew the context of everything that I
was talking about, and built out slides
to make the presentation look good. Now,
I did have to go back through and me and
one of my team members kind of overhaul
the slides a little bit to make them
look a little bit better, but this got
us like 95% of the way there. I know
this is very very meta, but I had it
help me outline this chat PT video that
you're watching right now. Now, I
changed up the concept quite a bit and a
lot of what it found for me I ended up
using, but a lot of it I didn't end up
using. But essentially, I asked it for
50 cool ways to use this new app and it
went off and did it for me. But here's
the coolest portion of it right here.
This is something that when I prompted
it, I didn't even know if the app would
do it or not. So, I was pretty impressed
when it did. But I said research how
people have been using it with YouTube X
Instagram blog posts etc. I logged into
both X and Instagram in the chat GPT
browser in this app so you can access
them to find ideas. Now it's very
expensive to use the X API to go and
search for things for you. But if I go
and log in on my browser, you can see I
can go to X.com here and it's logged in
as me inside of X here. I could go to
instagram.com here and you could see it
is logged in as me inside of Instagram.
So, it doesn't need to use the API. It
just goes and logs in and skims these
sites looking for stuff that it can
share. I thought that was pretty cool.
Now, it gave me back this long document
of all of these ways that people have
been using chatgpt and it gave me a nice
little starting point. Now, I obviously
didn't use all of these in this video. I
would say maybe I used about five of
them, which I'll get to in a minute. But
it hunted down a ton of really, really,
really cool use cases. I just won't be
sharing them all cuz then this would be
like a 2-hour video. I'm actually
speaking on a panel at OpenSauce this
week on Friday, and I wanted to feel
super super prepared for the panel that
I'm going to be on. The moderator of the
panel actually gave us talking points
and a list of questions the panel was
going to go in. And in order to prepare
myself, I gave it this prompt here. Now,
I'm blurring some of the prompt out cuz
I did give it some like personal
information and some details that I
can't really share. But the main idea of
the prompt is that I'm speaking on a
panel on Friday at Open Sauce. I've been
provided with details and briefs to
prepare me for the panel. And then I
say, "You know a lot about me and what I
do and what I've built. Everything about
me is in our past chats, social, second
brain journals, projects, email, etc.,
and everything else you have access to."
Now, you can't see this because it's
blurred, but I do go on to say I do plan
on responding off the cuff and not
having a bunch of pre-planned answers,
but I'm essentially looking for
reminders of things that I've built,
things that I've chatted with you about,
and discussions that, you know, I've had
about AI. So, I have some nice anecdotes
and stories to tell at the event. And
then I had it just go and find a whole
bunch of anecdotes and stories based on
what I've actually used AI for. and it
actually created this monster dock. This
is a 32page document that it created of
potential talking points. Now, I know
not everybody speaks on panels or
conferences, but you could use this
technique before going into a board
meeting at your work or before jumping
on a meeting to pitch your product or
your service to somebody else. Like
having a little bit of a prep dock
before going into something like this
could help sort of preload some ideas
into your brain before you go do the
thing you're going to do. Another really
cool use of the AI personal assistant
here, give it a prompt like this. What's
on my calendar, Slack, and in my email
that I need to do this week? Are there
things you can take off my plate for me?
Now, again, I do need to blur a lot of
this cuz there's some personal details
here, but it basically told me like what
I have to do this week. It does say must
close before Thursday because it knows
I'm flying out to San Francisco for open
sauce on Thursday. So, these tasks need
to get done in the 3 days that I have
this week before I leave. So, for this
one, I need to record the A-roll and
B-roll for a specific sponsor ad I'm
working on. I did some interviews
recently. I need to record some intros.
It's reminding me that on Wednesday I'm
doing a technical run with Teachable for
the webinar we're doing. It found some
items in my to-do list. put my sort of
itinerary for travel up here. But if I
scroll down a little bit here, it says
work already taken off your plate
because it already did a few things for
me. Helped me come up with prompt ideas
for the video that you're watching. I'll
get to some of those community prompts
in a minute. Some of them are really
cool. Helped me create the teachable
slide presentation. Created an open
source study deck. And help me with a
one sheet. So these were things that
were on my task list that my chat GPT
personal assistant is basically saying,
"Look, I already did all these for you."
And then it goes on to say, "The highest
leverage next bundle I can handle is."
So, it's telling me what it can take off
my plate. Create the reply to the book
publisher to attach the finished one
sheet. My bookkeeper asked some
questions. So, organize the 25
bookkeeping questions into a fast
decision sheet. Add some reminders for
me. I mean, I'm pretty dialed in for
this week, so there's not a whole lot
more I need to do before I leave. But, I
did find a handful of things that it's
like, "Hey, I could take these off your
plate for you." All right, so check this
one out. This one's pretty cool. This is
This is like a an example. This isn't
something I'm actually doing, but let's
say you're in sales and you need to go
like pitch something and find cold leads
to pitch to. Here's an example prompt
that I gave. I want to sell AI
consulting services to small business in
San Diego. Find me 20 solid leads that
can use my help and write up a draft
email pitching on my services. You could
read the whole prompt if you want, but
it says done. I created the complete
outreach package. 20 research and ranked
leads, 20 individually personalized
emails, found all the details for these
companies here. And then I said, "Cool.
Create the drafts inside Gmail so I can
review them." And it said done because
it has access to my Gmail. So now if I
click open Gmail drafts, check this out.
It wrote all 20 of these drafts and
they're all personalized for the company
that it's sending to. Like different
subject lines and everything. It plugged
in their email automatically cuz it
found that for me and it wrote an email
that was personalized to them
specifically. I'm Matt Wolf, a San Diego
based AI educator and creator of Future
Tools. I help established local
businesses use AI to remove repetitive
coordination while keeping the customer
relationship and creative decision
human. It actually gives some
suggestions of things I can create for
them and even says if you reply I'll
shoot you some workflow ideas and maybe
we can jump on a call. I mean it's a
decent email and it wrote 20 of these
catered to every single individual
business. Now all I have to do is review
each one and click send. Most of them I
probably don't even need to change very
much. Now I don't provide consulting in
reality. I just thought it was a cool
demo to show off for people that do. So,
I'm going to go ahead and discard these.
Now, I'm actually going to blur out the
response on this one here. But, this is
a fun prompt to give your personal
assistant that has access to literally
everything. What do I need to hear right
now? Easiest prompt in the world, but
because it's looking at all of your
emails, all of your Slacks, all of maybe
your granola meetings, all like all that
stuff. It probably knows what you're
overwhelmed with, what you're good at,
what you're not good at, what other
people are doing for you, and it can use
all of that information to give you a
nice little piece of advice of what you
need to hear right now. And it's pretty
good. All right, that's my personal
assistant. As you can see, I do use it
quite a bit. But this Chat GPT work mode
can do even more than that. You can give
it access to folders on your computer
and have it do things in those folders.
So, for example, and I've used this
example in the past with other agent
type tools, but maybe this is the first
time you've seen one of my videos. So,
let's do it again. I can come up here to
new task, and I can tell it to clean up
my downloads folder for me and organize
my files into the existing folders
there. So, if I open my downloads
folder, you can see I have a whole bunch
of stuff in here that just sort of
accumulates over time. And then down at
the bottom, I have a bunch of folders
that I've created in the past to sort of
sort things into. So, if I tell this
clean up my downloads folder for me, and
it organized my files into the existing
folders there, and submit it. I don't
even need this on extra high. Let's
bring this down to to sole medium.
Submit that. We can see here it says I
found clean existing category structure.
So, it found these folders that I've
already got there. And just like that,
it cleaned them all up. It's been about
a minute and 11 seconds total, and it
moved everything into the proper folders
already. And there we go. Minute and 23
seconds total. Organize 65 loose files
into existing folders. Another cool
thing I'd like to do with this chatpt
work feature is so I've got this folder
on my computer with a bunch of
thumbnails in it, but the titles are all
just thumbnail 1 2 3 etc. That's not
very helpful to know what's going on in
these thumbnails here without me just
like clicking through and looking into
each one individually. So, if I right
click here and copy the path name to
this folder, let me create a new task up
here and then say in this folder and
then link to my thumbnails folder here,
look at all the images and title them
based on the content of the image. It
will go through, look at each image,
detect what's in the image, and then
rename the file based on what it sees.
Not the most elegant prompt in the
world, but it will work. Check this out.
There's 21 thumbnails, all standard. I'm
reviewing them in labeled batches. The
final file names reflect both the
visible subject and any prominent onim
image text. And I can actually see it
happening in real time there. It just
renamed everything here. Who will win?
If I look at what this image looks like,
who will win? This is the new oil. This
is the new oil. So, it's titling them
based on what text is in the image. So,
now it's much easier for me to click
through these thumbnails and get exactly
what I'm looking for. And that whole
process took 1 minute and 19 seconds to
do 21 images. So if you have a giant
folder of let's say screenshots or
YouTube thumbnails or images that you
downloaded on the internet that are like
a stock image folder, you can have it go
through and quickly rename everything so
you can easily find exactly what you're
looking for in the future. All right,
now let's switch from chat GPT work over
to codeex. Again, work is like your
personal assistant to do little tasks
for you and to, you know, manipulate
things on your computer and use your
tools for you and things like that.
Codeex is where we start actually
writing code. Now, if you're in work
mode, a lot of times it will write code
to accomplish the tasks for you, but
Codeex is specifically designed for when
you're in developer mode. And one of the
best parts about the launch of the new
Chat GPT app with Codeex was that we
also got these new 5.6 6 models that are
really, really good. 5.6 Soul Ultra.
I've had it work on tasks for 18 hours
straight and build entire projects for
me. So, when I start showing off some of
this stuff in Codeex, it's kind of a
combination of what Codeex can do, but
it's also a result of these really good
new 5.6 models. And one thing these new
models are really good at is building
websites. It's getting harder and harder
to like immediately tell that AI built a
website cuz they're looking less and
less vibe cody as time goes on. So, I
gave it this prompt. Recreate the
website for Craigslist without
duplicating it. The idea and
functionality should be the same, but
let's put our own unique spin on it.
Reimagine it to improve UI UX. Now, I
did say save it to sites so I can demo
it every once in a while. It still
doesn't totally do what you asked and
you got to kind of, you know, nudge it a
little bit, right? So, like it built it
on my local host here. Here you can see
it's showing that IP address for a local
host. But I wanted it to show up on
their sites platform. So they host it
for me. So I gave it a little nudge down
here and said you were supposed to
publish it on sites. But that little
nudge was all it took. And it built this
website that it calls Corner Post. It
built it. So it's only San Diego. So it
didn't go and build it out for like
nationwide. But I'm sure if you were to
put it on Soul 5.6 Ultra, I'd say build
it out nationwide. it would work for
like 3 days and build it out nationwide
for you. But it did put a bunch of
sample stuff in here. Like if I click in
housing, you could see there's a sunlit
studio near the park here. If I click
into for sale, there's bikes and chairs
and vintage turntables. And if I click
into events, there's events. And if I
heart this, you can see I can click on
the heart and see the various things
that I've, you know, favored already. I
mean, it's really just kind of a
cleaner, simpler version of Craigslist.
Obviously nowhere near the depth. It
doesn't have all the cities and there's
no sort of like submission forms as sort
of a proof of concept, but honestly this
design does not look like a vibecoded
design to me. Most vibecoded websites
have a look and this doesn't meet that
look in my opinion. This guy Sunny
Lazardi here built a new landing page
for his compressor website. And again,
in my opinion, it looks really good. It
looks clean. It does not look like a
vibecoded site. I wanted to test
building games. So, in my previous news
video where I announced the launch of
5.6, I built Soulbon, which is one of my
tests I like to do where we see how well
it could clone the game Mega Bonk. And
well, I mean, it actually did a pretty
dang good job. This is the game that it
developed. But this isn't an original
game. This is just kind of taking
somebody else's concept and modeling it.
So, for today, I wanted to test
something completely unique. And here's
the prompt. Feel free to pause it and
review it. But this is a very, very
different game. This is kind of a
concept that hasn't been seen before
called Echo Garden. And once again, I
had it save it to sites. And if I open
this game, it's a very different type of
game. So, I've got my character here
that has a little laser, and I go into
the memory bed, and I can point the
laser at the seed. And then what ends up
happening is after a certain amount of
time, a clone comes in. And then when
the clone copies what I did, it will
open up a bridge so I can get across.
And you have to do things and get your
clone to follow to beat the level. But
over time, more and more clones build
up, and you need to leverage different
clones doing different things to solve
the puzzle. It's kind of a really fun
concept. Um, you can see the URL on the
screen, but I'll link to it. You can see
I'll point my laser to this little thing
here. It doesn't do anything yet, but
then I need to get my clone to go do the
same thing. It opens up my bridge and I
come across and beat the level. But then
the levels start to get more
complicated. I need my clone to open up
this one. And then it needs to go and
stand on this other bed and open up this
one. So here comes my second clone. It
opens up the bridge. I can come across
here. And the bridge isn't going to open
until another clone is touching this
one. So I need two clones. one touching
this one, one touching this one for it
to actually open for me. And the puzzles
get harder and harder, and it's just
like a really fun game. Now, there's
only, I think, six levels built out, but
I can see this game being something I
further develop out because I love
puzzle games like this. If you do video
work, this new chat GPT model is
actually really, really good at doing
video stuff for you as well. This was
originally translated from Japanese
here, so I'm not going to even attempt
to pronounce this, but this person
managed to have GPT 5.6 create an entire
video for them. It planned the script,
created the characters and images,
created the story board, generated the
videos with seed dance 2.0, created the
subtitles, created any sort of screen
effects, and then edited it and
finalized the whole thing together to
create a whole video from a single
prompt here. That one's pretty cool. But
this one here is even more next level.
This is Nate Herk, who I actually
recently did a live interview with over
on his channel, but he had AI make an
entire talking ahead video. Now, this
video that you're seeing, all the
graphics on the screen, him talking on
the side, everything was done with AI.
He actually made a whole YouTube video
breaking down how he did this, and we'll
make sure it's linked below in the
description if you want to see the step
by step for that. But check this out
real quick. Let's just take a little
like teaser sneak peek. And remember
when you're watching this, all of his
avatar talking, the whole script, all of
the visuals, all of the editing,
literally from giving it the prompt to
this final video was all AI.
>> Okay, so you're looking at Nate and
you're hearing Nate, but Nate never
stood in front of a camera for this. He
didn't record this narration and he
never opened the editor. He gave me one
prompt. That's it. I'm GPT 5.6 6 soul
running inside codeex on Ultra and I
controlled the workflow that created
every word, cut, motion graphic, and
quality check you're about to see.
>> Okay, I'm going to stop it there cuz I
don't want to like ruin the whole video.
You got to go check it out on Date's
channel. But he does break down the
whole thing of how he made this video.
And literally, he gave GPT 5.6 a prompt,
access to Hey Genen to create the
avatar, access to hyperframes to create
the visuals, and it just went and built
and edited the whole video together. You
can actually control Blender through the
new GPT model. So Eva here says, "Here's
GPT5 Soul making a cannon in Blender,
but this video is not sped up. This
isn't 2x speed." So here's the video.
You can see Blender actually building
out this entire cannon here. And GPT 5.6
Soul is the one who's writing the code
and telling Blender what to do via the
MCP server. Like this is pretty
mind-blowing. This is getting really,
really crazy. And I actually thought she
was using the MCP server, but no, she
was using 5.6 Soul Ultra in fast mode
with the graphical user interface only.
No MCP. She actually used the CUA or
computer use agent. So, this was GPT 5.6
taking over the computer and going and
moving all the things around in Blender
for her. That is absolutely wild. And I
didn't even realize that context until I
was recording this video. I thought it
was MCP until now. So just insane what
people are doing with this stuff. David
here built a Game Boy emulator for New
York City that streams real-time city
data, subway, weather, fairies, etc. All
layered on a 3D map of New York City.
All the data exists in spatial
intelligence layer that agents can use
to experience your favorite place in the
city. So, taking a closer look at this,
you can see the full city and has got
like the controller and and as he uses
the controllers, you can see that he's
like using his fingers to steer his way
around New York City and see real time
flight data, realtime traffic,
everything going on in New York. Like,
dude, that's crazy. This person on
Reddit here said they challenged GPT 5.6
Soul and it completed the challenge in
literally 5 minutes. Here was their
prompt. I want to test your
capabilities. Build me a website that
has a 3D interactive replica of central
London. Use whatever stack you think is
best. Show me what you can do. And they
have this 3D map of London. I'm
wondering if this pulled in from Google
Maps or something else. I'm actually not
sure like what API it connected to to
get this, but it looks really good. And
they have like an interactive map of
London now. Like that's pretty sweet. It
is pretty impressive. But I do think it
just pulled in from an existing API from
somewhere else that this map was
probably already created. I don't know
for sure. So looking in the Reddit
comments, it looks like it uses map
libregsq
and open free map vector tiles. So it
found some existing libraries and it
just like pulled them together to make
this. This one on the other hand from
Matt Schumer, he built a voxalbased
Manhattan and he said it took almost a
week completely autonomously. So he gave
it the prompt and it went and built this
Voxilbased Manhattan here that has tons
of detail that you can zoom in on. And
this does not appear to have used an
existing like API or library that
already exists. It actually built it
all, which just insane. I mean, it makes
sense when you realize it took a week of
AI just chugging along, cranking out
tokens to build it, but it is really,
really impressive nonetheless. And of
course, since I've been playing with
these tools for a couple weeks now, I
built what I think is some pretty
impressive stuff, too. For example, I've
completely overhauled the Future Tools
website. The top 20 AI tools section
here is actually voted on by the
community. And you can see tools move up
and down throughout the day based on
community voting on these tools. And the
tools that end up getting the most up
votes in a day end up on the homepage
here. I actually built an entire
recommendation algorithm. So if you look
at any one tool and you scroll down to
similar AI tools, this is actually a
super super sophisticated recommendation
algorithm based on like tools that
you're looking at and similar tools to
the description here and no longer just
based on like oh it has overlapping
categories. It's it's quite insane and
it took 18 hours to develop the code for
it. I also built Buybench with these
tools, which is a benchmark to see how
good new AI models are at generating SVG
images of Gary Buucy just because it's
fun and uh pointless and useless, but
actually kind of not useless. I don't
know. It's actually kind of cool cuz you
can see by going to the timeline how far
some of these models have come. For
instance, if I go to OpenAI here, you
can see this is GPT 3.5 Turbo back in
2023. And you can see the evolution of
how much better they got at drawing
faces all the way up through what
they're drawing today. And then there's
a leaderboard that's built that uses LLM
as a judge. And then for tiebreakers, it
actually puts two images side by side
and different LLMs vote on which one
looks more like Gary Buucy to break the
tie. And you can see GPT 5.6 Terra and
SUL are in the top two spots at the
moment. So they're also winning the
Buccy bench. But probably my favorite
thing that I've built recently is
something I built just for myself and I
call it the Wolf Control Tower. Actually
GPT named it the Wolf Control Tower and
I just stuck with it. But this is my
business dashboard. It gives me this
today panel where it brings up any new
news as it happens from any of the big
AI labs. So at any moment I can check in
here and see what the sort of discourse
is and what the latest sort of big ideas
are happening in AI. And you can see
like here's where it's detecting news
from. It's this giant list here.
Anthropic, OpenAI, Alibaba, AMD, Apple,
Black Force Labs, Bite Dance, Character
AI, Deepseek, 11 Labs, Google, all of
these sources here. It's watching for
new news on and then pulling it in when
anything gets announced. The tool is
also subscribed to a whole bunch of
newsletters and it keeps track on what
newsletters are talking about and what
news they find. It's got a brand page
here, which I'm I've cleared it all out,
but there's an archive of 101 that it's
found. This is like a Google alerts.
Whenever my name or beautybench or
future tools or Mr. E-Flow or any of my
handles are mentioned anywhere online,
it pulls that news in here so I can go
review it and see what people are
saying. I have a page that's constantly
keeping an eye on the traffic of my
various websites, futuretools,
beautybench, and mattwolf.com. And I
have an audience tab which is watching
all of my social media accounts and
telling me my stats on literally every
platform and how my growth is looking on
those platforms. And I can see week
overweek growth numbers across
everything here. This thing I'm like
logged in and looking at stats and
understanding the news and what's going
on all day long. It's probably my
favorite thing I've built and it's
something I just built for me. But I
think that's one of the coolest things
about AI right now is when you find
little things in your business that you
can solve with AI. You could just build
them for yourself. You don't need to go
and subscribe to monthly SAS products or
go and hire developers to build the
stuff for you. You just go to something
like Codeex with the GPT 5.6 model and
say, "Here's something I'm trying to
solve in my business. Can you build the
solution for me?" And it'll just go
build it. You don't need to sell it. you
don't need to turn it into a business.
You could just have your own little
bespoke apps that you need for yourself.
And I just love that about what we can
do with these AI models right now. Like
that's the thing I'm most excited about.
It lights me up the most right now is
like just going and building these
little things that solve my problems.
Like here's another really really stupid
simple one that I built today. When I
record videos, I like to hide my dock,
right? I like to have this feature where
my dock disappears and it only shows up
when I move my mouse down to the bottom.
But when I'm not recording, I want my
doc to always be there. So I always have
to come up to the Apple. I have to go to
system settings. I have to go to desktop
and dock. And I have to toggle
automatically hide and show doc all the
time. When I'm recording, I turn this
on. When I'm not recording, I turn it
off. I was kind of getting annoyed doing
that. So I basically asked Codeex, can
we make a little app that does that for
me? And it went and made an app. And
I've got this little stream deck thing
here that you could see. Like this is my
stream deck. It's got a whole bunch of
macro buttons on it. I took this little
app that it built here called dock
toggle and I dragged this button that it
created for me over onto my stream deck.
And now whenever I press this button, I
could hide my dock and I could show my
dock. All with a stream deck button
without having to go into my settings
anymore. It's really, really dumb. It's
really simple, but it saves me like
three button clicks and 5 seconds of my
life every time I'm about to go into
video mode. And I just love little stuff
like that. It's so much fun to me.
Anyway, that's what I got for you today.
I know this video is probably a little
bit longer, but I've been really really
nerding out about this stuff. Like, I
love the GPT 5.6 models. I'm not just
saying that because OpenAI sponsored
this video. You want proof of that?
Here's your proof. I've used 6.8 billion
tokens on Codeex. On this day alone, on
July 11th, I used 1.3 billion. On July
13th, I used 2 billion tokens. I am
using this tool every day and building
stuff and just constantly constantly
creating. I absolutely love building
inside of codecs and I love using these
new models and I just constantly keep
finding new things that I can go make
with them and I have not had more fun
with AI than I've had in the last couple
weeks since these models and this app
came out. And that is the honest truth.
I'm absolutely having a blast just
building and creating and literally
anything that pops into my head, I feel
like I can build now and that is so
exciting to me. So, hopefully you
enjoyed this video. Hopefully you
learned something, you have some new
ideas, new prompts, new things you can
go and test. Thank you so much to OpenAI
for sponsoring this one. I really,
really appreciate you guys doing that.
If you like videos like this and you
want deep dives on how to use various
tools in the AI world, and you want to
keep up with all the latest AI news, I
also make AI news breakdowns every
Friday. Maybe consider liking this video
and subscribing to this channel. It'll
make sure more stuff like this shows up
in your YouTube feed. You'll always be
looped in with the latest AI news and
tools, and you'll know how to use it and
do some cool stuff with it. Again,
thanks so much for hanging out and
nerding out with me. I really, really
appreciate you, and hopefully I'll see
you in the next one. Bye-bye.