So, I just built a second brain
knowledge management system that has an
entire wiki built in that I can chat
with. It will pull any information from
that second brain when I chat. It's got
a built-in CRM. I can journal, and it
will actually look at my wiki knowledge
base and try to help me with whatever
issues I'm going through from my journal
by looking inside of the wiki. And of
course, it's got all of the content that
I've saved from around the web,
including YouTube videos and articles
and tweets and podcasts and just tons of
stuff that I've injected into this that
is all accessible directly from a chat
or from journaling. It is really, really
sweet, and I'm going to break down how
the whole thing works and how you can
build one for yourself right now. Most
second brain systems are just like
storage, right? You dump your YouTube
transcripts and your articles and your
blog posts and your podcasts and just
everything that you're interested in,
you just dump it all into one place.
Problem is, that's kind of where the
information just goes to die. Unless
you're like actively going back through
and reviewing the notes all the time and
searching through your second brain,
it's just a dumping ground for
information that I never go back and
look at later. So, for the knowledge
management system that I'm going to
build, there's three core pillars that I
want to build for mine. Number one is
the wiki/knowledge base. This is where
I'm going to store like everything from
around the web that I find. YouTube
transcripts, articles, podcast
transcripts, tweets, you name it, it all
goes into this wiki knowledge base
section. Number two is my CRM. So,
whenever I go to a events and I meet
people or I jump on Zoom calls with
people, I want to remember those
conversations and I want to be able to
recall them in the future. I also want
to store details about those people, how
I met them, where I met them, some of
the discussions we had, any sort of
contact details I got from them, email,
phone number, address, whatever. They
can all live in this sort of CRM element
of this bigger second brain that I'm
building. And the third element is where
this all gets pulled together, and And
the journal. Now, I'm a big journaler. I
journal pretty much every single day.
When I have good days, I journal about
what went right, the things I'm excited
about, gratitude, that sort of stuff.
When I have rough days, I journal about
the things that are bothering me. My
videos not performing as well as I want
them to, having a creative block and not
knowing what to make videos about. I do
a lot of travel and I debate a lot about
whether the travel's going to be worth
it or not. I journal about pretty much
everything in my business. So, these are
my three ideal inputs. For you, it might
be clients or workouts, research papers,
recipes, sales calls, classroom notes.
The point is, the knowledge base sits at
the center and then everything else sort
of connects to it. The two elements that
I think are probably the most useful to
the most amount of people are going to
be the wiki and the journal. Maybe the
CRM isn't what you need. Again, maybe
it's your classroom notes, your
workouts, your recipes, et cetera. So,
here's a rough drawing of what I have in
mind. So, you've got your knowledge base
that lives at the center of all of this.
All of this knowledge is going to live
in Obsidian. I'll get into the whole
building process in a second. You're
going to save articles from around the
web, YouTube videos, you know, podcast
notes, whatever you find around the web
that's relevant to you, you're going to
save it with a simple Chrome web clipper
and it's going to save into your
knowledge base. The CRM that I just
mentioned, notes about people you met
and where you met them and all that kind
of stuff gets saved to the knowledge
base. Meeting notes, I personally use
Granola to record my meetings and take
notes for me. Those meeting notes can
automatically be injected into the
knowledge base. And then you have
journal entries. This is the layer where
you actually interact with your
knowledge base. You journal on what
you're dealing with right now and
ideally it's going to pull from the
knowledge base that has all of this
other information in it to ground the
responses to your journal entries. This
will make more sense as I go. Please
excuse the PowerPoint style slide here,
but I really want to explain what I'm
trying to build. So, here's the system I
imagine. You save your articles, your
transcripts, et cetera, into this
system. We'll do that using a web
clipper. The AI layer in the background
that we're going to build then
summarizes this stuff for us. So, it's
not just a giant transcript, it's
actually sort of the bullets and just
the information we need to know. The AI
is also going to extract people,
companies, tools, ideas, and themes, and
sort of break those off. That's where it
becomes kind of like a wiki. You could
click into the tools page and it will
list off all the tools that have been
mentioned across everything that we've
saved. You can click into one of the
tools and it will mention where and what
video that came from. And that goes for
all of these little categories here. I
also wanted to auto-link related notes.
So, if I have multiple videos about how
to build something with OpenClaw, they
all get cross-referenced to each other
and I can click around and sort of jump
into others. If you're familiar with
other second brain systems or like the
Zettelkasten system, it's essentially
that same concept of interlinking. I'm
then going to let the journal directly
into the system. So, when I do write
journals, it responds like ChatGPT, but
it's actually grounded in my own saved
knowledge. So, it's not going to just
respond with what ChatGPT would have
responded with. It's going to respond
with something like, "I see you're
struggling with ideas for videos. Well,
you saved this video 3 days ago that
says you should do this, this, and this.
You also saved this video 2 weeks ago
that gave this advice when you're
struggling with video ideas." And it
will actually pull from the knowledge
that I've saved, making it more tailored
to exactly what interested me and what I
found valuable over time as I save stuff
into the system. It's also going to use
AI to find patterns from past journal
entries. So, if I'm constantly
journaling on the same thing over and
over again, the same struggle, it's
going to see that as a pattern and take
that into account when it's responding
to my next journal entries. It should
resurface relevant ideas when I need
them, and it should also let me save
notes about people and connect those
people to ideas, companies, events, and
conversations. So, the CRM and the
meeting notes that I'm constantly
saving, that should also be connected to
ideas and journal entries and all of it
sort of pulled together in this big
mashup of like here's the conversations
I've had, here's what I'm journaling on,
here's what I've saved that I found
interesting, and it's all in this big
old soup of content that I'm saving, but
that big old soup of content that I'm
saving is the grounded information that
is getting pulled when I write my
journal entries and then get a chat
response based on those journal entries.
All right, now that I've completely over
explained this, let's just jump into the
process I'm going through to build this.
>> There's a cool new feature from
Hostinger that's made for deploying AI
agents at home. So, if you've ever
wanted to run something like OpenClaw,
but don't know where to start or find it
really complicated, this is going to
make the process a lot easier. I
actually use OpenClaw myself, so I can
attest that the setup can get pretty
technical. Right now, it's deployed on
my DGX Spark and my favorite thing it
built is simple CRM that when I meet
people at events, I can save quick notes
in Slack and then later ask it to remind
me what we talked about. So, it's great
for automating everyday things like that
to full-on businesses and these huge
agentic systems, which I've also seen
people do. And this new feature from
Hostinger makes it a lot easier to set
up. You can either pick a managed
OpenClaw plan or a VPS option. The
managed version is honestly the easiest.
It's a one-click deployment that
includes built-in AI credits, web
scraping already connected, and they
handle the updates, backups, and
security for you. You just go to the
OpenClaw landing page on Hostinger,
click get OpenClaw, choose your plan,
and by the way, if you do the 12- or
24-month option, it's even cheaper per
month. Then, during setup, you choose
your AI provider, pick your
communication channel like Telegram or
WhatsApp, and launch. And then, once
it's live, your agent runs 24/7. AI
agents like this used to feel very
gatekept. Like, only the really
technical people or big enterprises were
able to use them, but now it's pretty
cool how easy it's become to set it up
and use it for yourself at home. So, if
you've wanted your own AI assistant
without the headache of managing servers
manually, this is probably the easiest
way I've seen to do it. Check it out at
the link in the description box, and to
save even more money, use my code Matt
Wolfe for an additional 10% off. And
thank you so much to Hostinger for
supporting my channel and sponsoring
this portion of today's video. Now,
before I go any further on this, I do
want to give credit where credit is due.
This whole LLM knowledge base idea came
straight from Andrej Karpathy. I
specifically took the idea of using
Obsidian as the front end. Obsidian sort
of helps organize and easily read
markdown files. I'm just sort of
extrapolating off of this idea and
adding my journaling element and my CRM
element to the wiki concept that Andre
laid out here. Now, in order to build
this, you're going to need a couple
tools. I'm going to build this in Codex
here. This has been sort of my IDE of
choice lately to do coding and projects
like this. This is free to download, and
you get a certain amount of usage on the
free ChatGPT plan, but you're going to
get the most out of it if you do end up
upgrading. I'm also using Obsidian here.
Again, this is just a giant markdown
organizer and reader. This is totally
free to get. You can find it over at
obsidian.md.
You're also going to want the Obsidian
web clipper. So, if you're on the
obsidian.md website, I can scroll all
the way to the bottom here, and you can
see there's a link for web clipper.
Click in there, click add to Chrome, and
you'll get this little Obsidian web
clipper that you can see here in my
Chrome. And if I click this, this is
what automatically creates a new
markdown file, a new note for whatever
page you're on. And the cool thing that
I really like about this Obsidian web
clipper is that it automatically pulls
the transcripts from any YouTube video.
So, if I come over here to YouTube and
click on one of my recent YouTube
videos, and then I come up to the
Obsidian web clipper, it'll take a
second to load, but it will eventually
load the entire transcript for this
whole video straight into Obsidian, and
that makes it really easy to inject any
YouTube video or any article you find
around the web directly into your
Obsidian vault. So, once you have
Obsidian installed on your computer,
create a brand new vault, and I'm going
to call it second brain, and I'm going
to save it in a folder on my computer
called second brain. Now, I'll open
that, and we'll create this new vault,
and you can see I have a fresh blank
vault with nothing in it yet except for
a little welcome message. Now, it's
important to remember where on your
computer you just saved this vault, cuz
that's going to be necessary in the next
step here. I'm going to delete this
welcome message. It's not going to be
necessary, and now we have a purely
empty clean vault. So, for the next
step, I'm going to jump into Codex, and
we're going to actually build the dang
thing. So, over on the left here inside
of Codex, I'm going to click on add new
project, and then I'm going to select
use an existing folder. It's going to
open up my browser here to pick the
folder, and I'm going to go to the exact
folder that we just set our Obsidian
vault up with. So, for me, it's this
second brain folder that I created here,
and we'll go ahead and open that, and
then you can see I now have a project
over here called second brain. So, to
start this off, we're going to build the
basic bones of our wiki. And luckily,
Andre Karpathy generously gave us this
GitHub page that explains exactly how
the wiki architecture works. So, the
initial sort of hard part of building
the wiki is already figured out for us.
We can just take this URL to this GitHub
post here, open up Codex, make sure
we're in our second brain project folder
here, and giving it the prompt build out
architecture based on Karpathy's LLM
wiki here. I'm linking to that page on
GitHub that we were just looking at, and
then I said the current second brain
folder is the folder that Obsidian is
connected to. It is currently empty, so
we're building from scratch. And let's
go ahead and let it build out the sort
of architecture bones for us based on
what Karpathy's already figured out. All
right, so it worked for about 5 minutes.
It actually built out a whole bunch of
extra files that it didn't need to
build. I don't know why it created 51
files. The architecture is actually
supposed to be pretty small for this.
So, I literally prompted it, "Please
remove all the extra crap and just build
what's explicitly called for in
Carpathy's game plan." And it says,
"Done. I pruned it back to the minimal
Carpathy game plan." And now we just
have these files built in. If we pop
open Obsidian here, you could see we've
got just the folders we need. We have
the raw folder, we have the wiki folder,
we have our agents.md file, our index.md
file, and our log.md file. We can see
here exactly what each of these is for.
The raw folder is for the immutable
source material. This is where the
original stuff goes. Raw/assets, this is
for optional local Obsidian attachments.
You got the wiki. This is the
AI-generated markdown files that it's
pulling from the raw content that we're
inputting. You have the agents.md file,
which basically explains how this whole
thing works. So, we can see it's got the
operations. When the user adds a source
and asks LLM to process it, it does all
these things. When the user asks a
question, it queries it this way. So, it
basically tells it how this agent should
operate. You have the index.md file.
This is basically the catalog of
everything that's in the wiki. And then
you have the log file, where whenever
you make updates or changes or add
things, it updates the log file. Super,
super simple. We're starting bare-bones
here. If I look directly in the folder,
we just have what you see inside of
Obsidian. So, now I'm going to make sure
that my Obsidian web clipper is dialed
in. So, I'll go ahead and click on this.
We'll click on settings. Make sure you
add the name of your vault right here
under the vault list. If you're in
Obsidian down in the very bottom left
corner down here, you can see this is
the name of the vault. So, make sure
it's the same name exactly. And then
over under default, you've got the
templates over here. Click on the
default template and make sure that you
select that Second Brain vault or
whatever you titled it. And then I'm
having mine pull in these properties.
The source title, the source URL, the
date that it was created. That's the
date that I'm saving it in the web
clipper, not the date that the article
was actually written, and it's adding an
automatic web clip tag to it. And then
for the note content, it's just pulling
in the content. A lot of this might
actually be set for you by default, but
if it's not, this is what it should look
like. Under note location, we're going
to change this to just say raw, because
that is the folder inside of our
Obsidian vault that we want it to dump
it inside of. All right, so I can close
out of this, and for the very first
thing I'm going to ingest, might as well
ingest the instructions for how to build
one of these wikis. I know it's very
meta, but I want it inside of my wiki.
I'll click on my little Obsidian clipper
button, and you can see the source
title, LLM Wiki, we've got our source
URL, the date I'm pulling this in, and
the tags for web clip. And then here is
all of the content of this page here.
We'll go ahead and click add to
Obsidian, and we can see it added it
directly inside of the raw folder here
inside of Obsidian. Now, nothing's going
to happen automatically. We actually
need it to tell it to process the files
inside of raw for anything to actually
happen. But let's add a few more things.
I'm going to look through my YouTube
history and ingest some of the recent
videos that I've watched, like this
video called how to trick your brain
into becoming so disciplined your
friends will be shocked by your success.
I love a lot of psychology and mindset
type videos, so if I want to ingest
this, I come up to my web clipper, and
you can see it's going to pull in the
entire transcript here. So I'm going to
go ahead and click add to Obsidian, and
once again, we've got another file here
under raw. Now, there's one issue that's
going to pop up when I pull in YouTube
videos, is it's not going to properly
know the channel name, because it's not
automatically pulling it in into any of
these properties. But I can go to codex
here and give it some additional
instructions. When I save a video from
YouTube using the Obsidian web clipper,
and then you go and process the files,
make sure it also pulls the channel name
from YouTube and adds it as one of the
front matter fields. All right, so let's
go ahead and do that. So now let's go
ahead and do a quick test. We've got two
source files in here. So I'm going to
jump into Codex and go ahead and tell it
to process the files inside the raw
folder. Let's see how well it does right
now. All right, so it took about 3
minutes to process and it created a few
new sections. So let's just go ahead and
pull open Obsidian here and we can see
it left the original source material
here, but then it started to build out
the wiki of everything else. So we've
got our compounding knowledge base which
was clearly pulled from the explanation
from Andre, discipline without
willpower. This was pulled from this
channel, Aaron Miller study. Let me just
double check that it got the channel
name correct. Yep, Aaron Merrill study,
environment design. We can see this was
from the source discipline without
willpower, which was one of the concepts
that it saved, which came from this
original video that we saved. Identity
led goals, LLM wiki, temporal
discounting, and temptation bundling. So
we can see our wiki is starting to get
built out we have our index here, our
various sources, the LLM wiki and the
discipline without willpower. It
actually renamed it cuz it was
originally called how to trick your
brain into becoming so disciplined your
friends will be shocked by your success,
but it decided discipline without
willpower was a better name for it. We
can see the concepts here and it's
starting to build out. And if we look in
our log, we can see what it registered
in our log so far since we started
building this. One thing that I actually
like to do as this gets bigger and
bigger is you've got this graph view
here that starts really small when you
first build it and over time you'll see
this build out and build out and things
get more interconnected with each other
and it just gets really cool over time.
Now, I'm going to go seed this with some
more content. I'm going to go through my
watch history and pull in some of the
other videos that I watched recently,
using your money to be happier, the art
of tripod filmmaking, how to become
addicted to doing hard things, if you
think you're too busy watch this, how to
become a lucky person, and then build
your own self-improving AI wiki in 11
minutes. I know that's very meta, but
let's go ahead and import that. So, I'm
just going to go through and inject
every single one of these like we just
saw. I'm going to let it process them
all, and then they'll all be in the
Wiki, and then we'll move on to the next
steps, which are building out the
journal and the CRM elements that I
mentioned earlier. Okay, so it's done
injecting all of those videos that I
just saved. It took about 6 minutes
here, and this is what my Obsidian looks
like now. You can see all of the assets
of stuff that I ingested into it, and
the Wiki is getting built out quite a
bit more. We've got our index here, and
as you can see, the index is also
getting built out more as well. If I
click into like Hermes agent here, we
can see we've got key ideas from this
original video plus related content
inside of our Wiki. So, Codex
capabilities, I click on this one, and
it jumps to the video from Riley Brown
and the details around that one. Again,
this is the very, very simple, basic
setup of Carpathys' LLM Wiki. Now, if I
come into Codex again, we can
essentially chat with the Wiki. So, I
come to my second brain folder, click on
new chat, and I can ask questions. Like,
what are some tips for motivation when I
don't feel like doing the hard task
today? I know I saved a couple videos
about this exact topic, and we can see
it's already saying, "I'll treat this as
a Wiki query. First, I'm checking the
vault index, then I'll answer from
anything already captured and add the
reusable bit back into the Wiki if it
isn't there yet." Here's our final
response. When you don't feel like doing
the hard task, don't wait for motivation
to arrive first. Treat it as a task
design problem. Make the first few
minutes smaller, easier, and more
rewarding. Try this. Gives me a handful
of tips, and this was all pulled and
grounded from the Wiki, but it also
updated the Wiki based on the question
that I asked. You can see that it
changed the index.md file, the log.md
file, and the Wiki motivation for hard
tasks. So, opening up my Obsidian vault
here again, looking in my log, we can
see that it actually logged this query,
motivation when avoiding a hard task,
answer to query about motivation, and it
even updated the index with it. And it
created motivation for hard tasks and
linked back to the original sources that
it found this information from. So, as
you ask questions, the wiki further and
further and further builds out based on
the questions you were asking. Now,
there's a few things that I want to do
to clean this up a little bit and make
it slightly more useful for me cuz right
now, once it processes something, it
just leaves it in this raw folder, and
this is just going to build up and build
up. And so, what I want to do is under
this raw folder here, I'm going to go
ahead and create a new folder, and I'm
going to call it processed. Whenever it
processes one of these files and adds it
to the wiki, I want it to move it to the
processed folder, so I know that that
has already been ingested. So, now that
I've got this processed folder, I can
simply come down to my agents file here
and then tweak what happens when the
file is processed. So, if I come down
here, we've got operations ingest when
the user adds a source and asks the LLM
to process it, read the source from raw,
create or update wiki pages, update
relevant entity concept topic overview
synthesis or comparison pages, update
index.md, append an entry to log.md.
Well, now I can just add a number six
and say move the source file from the
root raw directory to raw/processed.
By adding that extra bit to the little
prompt here, now it's going to go
through all these steps, but then move
it into the processed folder. It also
misunderstood me when I said to add the
channel name. It thought I wanted it to
add the channel name to the actual wiki
generated page, but I wanted it to add
the channel name to the original source.
That's what makes the most sense to me.
So, I'm going to come to my agents
section here and just tweak that as
well. So, right now it says for YouTube
videos clipped with Obsidian Web
Clipper, also open or inspect the
YouTube source URL and add the channel
name to the generated wiki page front
matter. But instead of that, I'm going
to say add the channel name to the
original source page front matter. I I
want it to link back to the original
source. So, I'm going to add a step
right after step three here and say
cross-link any wiki pages generated or
updated to the original source page.
Basically, I don't want these pages
orphaned. If there's a new wiki page
here, I want it to link to the original
page here. So, that's the manual way to
update the agents.md file, but you can
also do it by prompting it inside of
Codex. So, if I come to my second brain
project, create a new chat here, I can
give it instructions on additional
things that I want to happen. So, I
mentioned my journal and I mentioned my
CRM. So, let me go ahead and build the
bones for that here. I will close these
folders to clean everything up. I will
create a new folder called journal and a
new folder called CRM. Now, I can come
to Codex and say update the agents.md
file to handle these items. Number one,
if I start a chat with journal, add the
text of that chat and subsequent
conversation as a new md file within the
journal folder. The entire conversation
should be added to the markdown file.
Create an index file in the journal
folder that's similar to the wiki index
file. Each new journal entry gets added
to the index file. Decide on a short
title for the journal entry based on the
contents of the journal and use the date
and the title as the journal entry file
name. Add the date and title to the
index and link to the entry. Also, log
the journal entry title and short
summary in the log.md file. Your
response to my journal entry should be
grounded in content from the wiki in the
same way you view the index and respond
to my chat questions based on what's in
the wiki. Provide advice and insights to
my journal entries based on what's
available in the wiki, as well as your
own LLM knowledge. Provide helpful
advice, insights, guidance, tactics, and
ideas using what you know, along with
what's available from the wiki, past
journal entries, and the CRM. So, when I
journal, I want it to look in the wiki,
find information that's helpful to what
I just journaled on. I want it to look
in past journal entries to see if
there's anything relevant I've journaled
on in the past, and I want it to look at
my CRM and see if there's conversations
I've had with people about what I'm
journaling about, too, for the CRM. If I
tell you I'm giving you information for
the CRM, either update the person in the
CRM or add the person to the CRM. CRM
file should always be a person's name. I
will share details about a person, their
name, contact details I have for them,
details about where or how we met,
things that I know about them, etc.
Creator, update the contact record in
the CRM with whatever details I give
you. In the CRM folder, create an index
file similar to our other index files
with the name of the people in the CRM
listed in alphabetical order and a short
bio of what information I have about
that person. This will allow me to ask
questions about contacts that are inside
the CRM. I want it to update these two
things in our agents.md file, which will
make it so that whenever I chat with my
second brain project here in Codex, it's
either one going to answer the question
that I asked it using the sort of query
task that's already built into the
agent, it's going to handle it as a
journal if I preempt it with journal
here, or if I tell the chatbot that it's
for the CRM, it will update the CRM
section. So, I'm going to let it go
ahead and update our agents.md file,
create the various index files, and that
should build out the system for these
elements. Okay, so we can see that it
updated the agents.md file with our
journal rules, our CRM rules, and if we
open up Obsidian once again, I can open
my journal folder and you can see we've
got an index with date entry and
summary, and if I open up my CRM, we've
got our index with the person and the
summary, and where most of the updates
happened was this agents.md file. So,
now below the wiki section, we have a
journal section. It built all the rules
that I just asked it to build for me,
and then we also have our CRM section.
So, it created all the rules for the CRM
section now. Let's jump into Codex one
more time and let's test this out. I'm
just going to say add to CRM, and then
I'll put Matthew Berman, and then I'll
just put met at Qualcomm event in 2024,
hung out at CES in 2025,
got lunch during TechCrunch disrupt in
2025, and then I would obviously add
whatever sort of contact details I have
about him, but no point in doing that on
camera. I'll just tell it to add that to
the CRM, and we can see updating the CRM
record for Matthew Berman, creating a
new record, and it says, "Great, I
created that." If I look in my Obsidian
here, we can see under CRM, we now have
a Matthew Berman in CRM here with our
summary, no contact details provided,
how we met, relationship context, and
you know, other stuff that's still empty
right now. And then if I look at my
index, we can see it added the person,
Matthew Berman, and a quick summary
there. It also added it to the log down
here that the CRM was updated. But the
idea being is, let's say I'm going to a
conference, and I bump into somebody,
and I'm like, "Oh, shoot, where did we
meet?" I can jump into my second brain
and say, "Where did I meet Matthew
Berman again?" I'll check the vault and
CRM records. You met Matthew Berman at
Qualcomm event in 2024 according to your
CRM notes. So, a really good way to
reference information later. I'm going
to go ahead and make a pretend journal.
So, what I'll do is I'll click on a new
chat inside of my second brain project
here, and I'll start it with journal,
and then I'll go to another line, and
I'll just brain dump some thoughts. So,
this is just a simple demo journal
entry, but you know, it's got some
reality to it. I have a ton of ideas for
videos, but I decide not to make them
because I'm worried they won't get a
good view count. I also talk about how I
know how to write titles that will get a
lot of clicks, but I also hate the whole
clickbait thing, so I end up making
titles that I know will get less clicks
because they're more literal to what the
video is about, and I constantly grapple
with making videos that will get a lot
of clicks, but knowing I'll get hate in
the comments because they're too
click-baity versus making videos that
the title is very literal, so I won't
get the hate comments, but I'll also get
a lot of less views. And that's
something that I grapple with, and I
know pretty much every YouTuber grapples
with. And so, that's my short journal
entry. So, let's go ahead and submit
that and see what happens. I'll treat
this as a journal entry and grab the
response in the vault first. Going to
read the indexes, look for relevant
prior notes around creating video
attention, then I'll write the journal
file before answering. The vault has
several creator strategy pages. I'm
pulling those in rather than answering
from a blank slate. There aren't prior
journal entries yet, and the CRM doesn't
appear relevant to this one. So, it's
just pulling from the wiki. Okay, and
check out this journal response here. I
think there are two fears braided
together here, creative integrity and
channel safety. One part of you does not
want to betray the video with a title
that feels gross. Another part is afraid
that a few underperformers will teach
YouTube not to trust you. The creator
notes in the vault push back on the
second fear. YouTube value of death and
creator persistence both frame visible
metrics as lagging indicators. A few
lower view videos are not a downward
spiral, blah blah blah. So, it is
actually grounding the response to my
journal in what is existing in the wiki.
And then it actually goes on to just
give a response that ChatGPT would
normally give, but it's pulling from
both the knowledge built into the LLM as
well as the knowledge in the wiki. So,
that's all working exactly as intended.
And then if I want to pop open Obsidian
here, I can open my journal folder, and
we can see here is my journal entry.
Here is what the assistant replied with.
Here's some synthesis, and here's some
related content about what I'm
journaling about. If I look at my index
here, it automatically logged the date,
the entry title, and a quick like one
paragraph summary of what my journal
entry is about. Now, I want some of this
to happen on autopilot. I don't want to
have to jump into Codex constantly and
tell it to process everything that I
saved in here. And there's an easy
solution for that. Before I show you,
I'm going to do one thing. I'm going to
go ahead and clean up my existing
Obsidian wiki because, remember, I want
these to all get moved into processed,
and I also want it to save the YouTube
channel name up here in the front
matter. So, I'm going to tell it,
"Please reprocess all of the files in
the raw directory following the recent
updated instructions on how to process
them." So, I'm going to let that
process. It's going to clean up my wiki
real quick. All right, now that that's
finished and my Obsidian vault is
cleaned up and we can see all of my
videos have been moved to process and it
added the channel name to the original
videos here. Let's automate some of
this. So, in Codex here, you've got a
feature called automations. This is
where you can set it up to do recurring
tasks. So, if I click into automations
here, select new automation. For
automation title, we'll call it process
second brain raw files. For work tree,
I'm going to set it on local so it runs
directly in the selected project. For
our project, we're going to select
second brain. Here, we'll select when we
want it to run. I'm going to go ahead
and set mine to hourly, but you can do
it at whatever cadence you want. And I'm
just going to say if there are any
unprocessed files inside the raw
directory, please process them now. For
the model, I'm going to set it as a
GPT-5.5.
I recommend just using the strongest
model you have available. I'm going to
set it on high reasoning and I will
create this automation. Now, it's going
to run every hour, see if there's
anything in my raw folder that's
unprocessed, and then it will process
it. And that's it. That's the whole
process now. Whenever I come across
stuff I want to save, I just use the
Obsidian web clipper and clip it into my
raw folder automatically. And every
hour, it's going to ingest that and turn
it into one of the wiki pages. If I want
to add somebody to my CRM, I just open
up Codex, create a new chat inside of
this project, and add the CRM details.
If I feel like journaling right now, I
can journal straight into my second
brain, and it will ground the response
in what's available in my wiki, past
journals, and within my CRM. If you want
an extra layer of backup, you can also
go to GitHub, create a new repository on
GitHub. I'm going to go ahead and call
this one second brain. I'm going to set
this to private, so it's only available
to me, and I'll create the repository.
Now, if I copy this URL, jump back over
to Codex here, I can say commit this
current version to my private GitHub
repo here. Pasting the URL of the
private GitHub repo I just created, and
then go ahead and submit it. Now, I've
previously attached the GitHub plugin,
so it should just work out of the box.
You can see I'm already synced with
GitHub, but if you haven't done that
already, just add the GitHub plugin and
go through the motions to get that set
up, and you should be good to go. And it
went ahead and pushed it to GitHub, so
if I open my browser here and refresh,
we can see everything I've created is
all saved on GitHub now. If I jump back
into Codex, I can go to my automation
and edit this automation and say if
there are any unprocessed files in the
raw directory, please process them now.
Once everything is processed, please
commit and push the current version of
the directory to the main branch on
GitHub. So, now it's going to process
everything in the raw directory, and
then once it's done processing, it's
going to update GitHub so that backup is
constantly happening every hour. And
there you have it. There's the whole
second brain process. Not only do you
have a wiki of all of the information
you're finding and saving from around
the internet, but now you have a journal
and a CRM that's built on top of it as
well. And if you ever want to tweak how
it operates, you just open up Obsidian,
which is your visibility layer to see
how everything is built, and you go into
agents.md, and you just tweak the
instructions. This is all just prompts
at the end of the day. You just change
how it gets prompted. And in the short
amount of time that we've been working
on it, this is what our graph view looks
like now, and we can start to see all of
these things interconnect with each
other a little bit more. Do this for a
few days and a few weeks, and the next
thing you know, you have a vault that
looks like this. Uh yeah, pretty insane,
crazy vault that just has a ton of
information saved inside of it. So, I
know that video was long. There was a
lot of details. I wanted to make sure it
was very clear and you got the whole
process, and I didn't skip any steps,
but I want to show you how I've been
building this sort of second brain
concept that I can journal on top of
that I have a CRM on top of where all of
the wiki elements are interconnected.
You can even dial it in more by building
in separate folders and telling it to
break out people from different pieces
of content and break out companies from
different pieces of content and really,
really dial in that wiki more and more
and more. But really, really cool
concept. All you really need is Obsidian
and Codex. Anthropic's co-work or Claude
code also works. Whatever your sort of
front-end chat platform of choice is.
I've been really liking Codex lately, so
that's what I've been using. But yeah,
go build it. It's really, really cool
and a lot simpler than you think and
over time it just gets smarter and
smarter and smarter and more and more
powerful. So, that's what I got for you.
This isn't like my normal videos. I
normally make end of week news
breakdowns where every single Friday I
break down all of the news that happened
in the AI world for the week. I drink
from the fire hose all week, keep up
with all of the news, keep myself
completely looped in so that other
people don't have to feel overwhelmed.
I'll take on the overwhelm and just
report what I think is the most
interesting. I put those videos out
every single Friday. If stuff like that,
as well as tutorials like this, are
something that interest you, maybe
consider liking this video and
subscribing to this channel. It really,
really helps me out a lot. But again,
that's what I got. Thanks for hanging
out with me, nerding out with me.
Hopefully, I'll see you in the next one.
Bye-bye.