HERE'S
the AI news you probably missed this
week. Starting with the thing that most
people have been talking about lately,
and that's that we finally got our Fable
5 back. Now, if you haven't been paying
attention, Fable 5 was released on June
9th, 2026, and it was pretty much the
best model anyone has ever seen,
including me. It worked really, really
well. Then, just a few days later on
June 12th, the US government basically
said, "No, this model is too dangerous
for it to be out in the public."
Apparently, some people at Amazon had
found some vulnerabilities with it,
reported them to the government, and got
Fable shut down. Fast forward to this
week, 2 and 1/2 weeks later, and on July
1st, they finally gave us our Fable 5
back. Now, the version that they
redeployed isn't exactly the same
version. Now, supposedly has all of the
same capabilities, but they did have to
build in some extra safeguards.
According to their article, the new
classifier comes at the cost of flagging
benign requests more often during
routine coding and debugging tasks. Now,
if you remember from the last time they
launched this product, the biggest
complaint was that it would not actually
do too many of the benign things that
people asked it to. Like really simple
stuff. It would say, "Sorry, due to
cyber security reasons, we can't answer
that." And it would push you to using
one of the Opus models instead. Well,
this new version apparently is going to
not answer even more of your benign
requests. They've got this handy little
chart here to show you this that benign
stuff is going to fall within this
larger safety margin and actually not
get sent to Fable and we'll probably
just get redirected to Opus. According
to this Bridgemind account over on X,
Fable 5 came back nerfed. They ran it on
their own benchmark and they said that
debugging went from an 86.2 down to a
25.9. Refactoring went from a 73.6 6 to
a 38.4 and Hallucinations went from 75.9
to 61.7. They do go on to say that when
the tasks are able to be completed by
Fable 5, it functions the same as it was
before, but the new guardrails are so
strict that it gets through way less.
And a lot of the comments kind of debate
this. Most people saying it actually
feels kind of the same. And honestly, so
far from my experience, it's yeah, felt
pretty much the same. I haven't actually
gotten blocked on any of my own tests
yet, but I'm also not trying anything
that I feel like should get blocked. So,
none of my benign requests are getting
blocked. I mean, check out some of this
stuff that I've been able to do here.
It's still really good at making games.
I made this whole Cube Basher game and
actually continually improved it more
and more. It's very much a Mega Bonk
clone, but it works really well. And the
graphics are surprisingly impressive.
like I can change my camera angles and
everything just looks good and works
good. I also used Fable to completely
build me a dashboard for creating short
form videos. So I can come up here,
click new short. I can give it a URL to
an article. I can copy and paste text. I
can drag and drop a file here. I can
give it directions on how to steer the
short. I can choose my target length. I
can tell it whether this short is
actually a promotion and give it details
about the sponsor. I can tell it if this
short includes an interview. And I can
select any model I want for it to
actually generate the script for this
short width. It generates the whole
script here. This one happens to be
based on an interview. It fact checks a
lot of what I say in this script to make
sure that I'm not saying anything that's
not true. I can give it feedback and it
will optimize and edit the script for
me. It has the formula that it used to
write the script. I can export it as a
doc so I can share it with my team. And
it even built a teleprompter for me,
which I don't really need cuz I've got a
teleprompter. that it built one for me
in here without me even asking it to.
But then it also goes and generates
B-roll for me. So if I click on B-roll
here, it actually uses Remotion behind
the scenes for the entire video,
generates B-roll to go along with the
script. So all I have to do is go and
record the script that it gave me into
my teleprompter here. And I have A-roll.
I go and download the video clips that
it generated for me here. And I overlay
this video as B-roll over the A-roll
that I recorded with my teleprompter.
So, it pretty much does most of the work
of generating shorts for me. Now, this
isn't an app that I'm going to be
sharing and making publicly available.
And the main reason is I designed it so
that it literally watches my shorts. It
watches my Instagram reels and it
watches my YouTube shorts, watches for
which ones are performing well and get a
lot of views and then constantly
optimizes to make the scripts better and
better based on what was working. Now, I
haven't tested making any videos with
this yet, but you get the idea here.
makes the script. It makes the B-roll.
Tells me where to put the B-roll. And
once it's done all that, I can literally
download each little video here by
coming up to the top and clicking
download all. And I can see exactly how
this whole thing got produced. This is
where my cost came from. So, I have an
audit log of every single video that I
make. This was built with Fable and it
was built within the last 24 hours or so
since this new version's been live. I
also built this app that generates
B-roll for me for long form videos. I
basically plug in an article here. Like
for instance, this article about
redeploying Fable 5. Let's paste this in
here. Open the article. And then I can
do things like highlight sections of the
article. Click save selection. Let's
highlight this. Click save selection.
And I'll go through and highlight a
bunch of stuff. I can even come down
here and pick images and highlight an
image and save that to the selection.
And then if I click capture page, it
creates this video for me where it
actually highlights the things that I
selected when I was highlighting it
originally, but it does it like in an
animated form. So it goes through and
all of the various sections, it's
highlighting them. And you'll see the
animation will scroll down the page and
highlight various things. And then if I
skip ahead in my video here, you'll
notice that at the end I selected an
image and it sort of like zooms in on
that image. So, it allows me to talk
about news articles, go and highlight
different things on the news article,
and then anything that I highlighted
creates video B-roll for me that I can
come up here and export. I built this
with Fable, but probably my crowning
achievement, the thing that I'm the
absolute most excited to share with you
is the brand new benchmark that I
created. I teased it in my previous
video called Beautybench. It's a
benchmark to test how well the various
AI models are at drawing SVG images of
Gary Buucy. And it is so much fun to go
through and see the evolution of how
these models were able to draw SVGs. Now
SVGs are not like an image generator
like Nano Banana or Dolly or Stable
Diffusion. It's actually using code to
draw these. So, if we go all the way
back to March 2023, this is what GPT 3.5
Turbo thought that Gary Buucy looked
like. This is roughly the model that the
original Chat GPT was using. Chat GPT
came out in November of 2022. So, this
Turbo model is slightly more advanced
than that, but it's roughly the original
Chat GPT model. And then over time, you
can kind of see how models evolved at
being able to generate SVGs. And some
models haven't evolved at all. But when
we get up to the top here, you could
actually see some pretty big jumps. So
by February of 2026, Gemini 3.1 was
drawing SVGs that looked like this and
like this. Gros actually, for some
reason, look more like doodles than they
do sort of lines and circles that SVGs
are known for. This entire benchmark and
website I created using Fable. Here's
what GPT 5.5 and 5.5 Pro think Gary
Buucy looks like in SVG form. And here's
what Fable thinks that Gary Buucy looks
like in SVG form. I'm partial to this
Fugu model here, but I also made it so
you can sort by cost, highest to lowest.
So, GPT 5.5, it cost me $4 to generate
this SVG with 5.5 Pro. 01 Pro cost me $3
to generate that. We can sort by tokens
used, which ones used the most tokens.
Grock 420 used 106,000 tokens to get me
this. We could sort by run duration.
Which one took the longest to generate?
GLM 5.1 took 6 minutes and 50 seconds to
generate this SVG here. I also built a
timeline page. So you can pick any sort
of model provider here and see the
evolution. So if I click on OpenAI,
it'll filter it down. And we can see it
starts here with GPT 3.5 Turbo. And over
time, you can see the improvements that
the OpenAI models have done at making
these SVG images all the way up until we
get to GPT 5.5 and 5.5 Pro. So, this is
the SVG of today. Well, you know, the
latest model that came out in April of
2026 versus what the original chat GPT
would have generated. I think my
favorite one to look at is Meta cuz
well, they just kind of never figured it
out. Although, I really like this image
here that Quinn generated, and it cost a
little over two cents to make. And while
I was at it, I figured I might as well
plug in the image generators as well.
This one isn't as built out as the SVGs,
but we can see how the various image
generators have evolved over time.
Starting with MidJourney V1, which came
out in February of 2022, all the way to
what we're getting now from Nano Banana
2 Light and GPT Image 2, which I think
is currently probably the winner. But
again, there's a lot of models I haven't
added in here yet. We've still got like
Crea models, ideoggram models, stable
diffusion models. So, this one isn't
quite as fleshed out as my uh Buy Bench
SVG test here. Why did I make Buucy
Bench? Not because I thought the world
needed it, but because it was just so
much fun to make. Like, I was just
playing with Fable and adding features
and testing new models. And I used Open
Router to go and just bulk generate with
tons and tons and tons of different
models. And I lost, you know, 2 days of
my life building beauty bench just
because I was having a lot of fun. And
sometimes just having fun with these AI
models is uh a good use of time. Like
what do they say? Time you enjoy wasting
is not wasted time or something like
that. That's why I built beauty bench.
But if I'm being honest, I actually
think it's a fairly legit show of how
these models are improving. It's
basically showing us, is this model
decent at writing code that can look
like faces? And you can definitely see a
very clear progression over time that
gives you an idea of how these models
are improving. But man, has it been fun
to make. Anyway, back to Fable 5 here.
One thing that is very important to note
is that if you're on one of the paid
plans, you get access to Fable 5, but
only through July 7th. So, by the time
you're watching this, you probably only
have like a couple days left to get in
and use Fable as much as you can on your
current account. After that, it's going
to be available via usage credits.
You're going to have to pay extra on top
of your existing plan in order to get
access to Fable. So, they're not giving
us a huge window to use this. So any big
projects that you have in mind, it's
probably a good idea to give them to
Fable, have Fable work on them and do
like the bulk of the work now and then
when you lose access to Fable, go back
to your favorite model of before, you
know, one of the Opus models or GPT 5.5
and let it make the more incremental
improvements, but let Fable do like the
big portion of the work now. Anyway,
that's what I'm doing with a lot of my
projects that have been on my list.
Another cool AI product I've heard a lot
about lately is GenSpark. And it's
basically an all-in-one AI workspace
that brings together a bunch of top AI
models and productivity tools into a
single platform. And one of their newest
features is called GenSpark Claw. It's
basically a readytouse version of
OpenClaw that runs in the cloud. You can
connect it to tools like Slack, Teams,
WhatsApp, Telegram, and more, and then
just tell it to do tasks for you. They
also have a desktop version that can
actually interact with files on your
computer and navigate the web on your
behalf. Another feature I thought was
really interesting is their upgraded AI
office suite. They've got AI slides, AI
sheets, and AI docs. For presentations,
there's this new guide mode that asks
questions before building your deck. And
if you want to change something, you can
literally click on an element and tell
it what to edit while keeping the rest
of the presentation consistent. The AI
sheets can pull data from spreadsheets,
databases, or online and automatically
generate formulas, charts, and
visualizations for you. And AI docs can
turn pretty much any word dump into a
polished, professionally formatted
document. Paid users currently get
unlimited AI chat and AI image
generation throughout 2026, subject to
abuse and guard rails, of course. And
they're also doing a get started bonus
where new users can try their premium
features for free. So, if you're
interested, check out the link in the
description. Users who sign up through
that link get free credits to try it
out. And thanks so much to GenSpark for
supporting my channel and sponsoring
this portion of today's video. Now,
let's move on to some other news that
came out late last week that is very
along similar lines to what we were just
talking about with Fable, and that's the
new GPT 5.6 models. Now, we actually
talked in last Friday's video about how
OpenAI is going to be releasing them,
but most people aren't going to get them
because the government wants to approve
them person by person or company by
company or I I don't know how that's
going to work. But GPT 5.6 was coming
out, but we normal people weren't going
to get to use it. Well, that came out on
Thursday and then OpenAI made that
official on Friday, basically saying,
"Hey, our next generation models are
here, but you can't have them." Now,
this model comes in three flavors.
You've got your Soul, your Terra, and
your Luna. And it kind of sounds like
maybe they're going in the direction
that like Anthropic went in where like
their biggest models were Opus and their
medium models were Sonnet and their
lowest models were Haiku. And I mean now
they have Mythos class on top of that.
But it kind of feels like they're going
in that same direction. Like Soul is
maybe their mythos class or Opus class.
I'm not quite sure. Somewhere between
Mythos and Opus. And then you have
Terra, which is kind of like their
sonnet. And then you have Luna, which is
like their haik coup, their smaller
models, but this sole model does appear
to be fairly on par with what you get
out of Fable. This is like their version
of Fable or Mythos or whatever you want
to call it. But the big difference here
is the price. Input $5, output $30. If
we compare that to Fable, Fable's input
is 10 and output is 50. So half the
price for input and almost half the
price for output. But if we look at the
benchmarks that they share here, this
GPT 5.6 Six. Soul Ultra, which I guess
that's probably a better way to look at
it. Soul Ultra is like their Fable,
where Soul is like their Opus. But Soul
Ultra on Terminal Bench scores a 91.9%
where Fable's all the way down here at
84.3%.
And their Terra, the sort of middle
Sonnet version, is tied with what Fable
is doing on Terminal Bench specifically.
Now, we don't really have a lot to go
off of for this model yet. They haven't
given us a ton of information other than
some of the pricing here. Artificial
Analysis doesn't have it within their
benchmarking yet at all. So, nothing
there. And again, their website is
leaning in heavily on showing off
Terminal Bench, one specific benchmark
about how well it runs terminal commands
essentially. But when we scroll down to
the availability and pricing section
during the preview, 5.6 models will
initially be available through the API
and codecs to a select group of trusted
partners and organizations. We plan to
make them more broadly available to
people using chat GPT codeex and the API
soon. Still no exact indication of when
we're going to get access to it, but my
guess is we'll probably get it within
the next couple weeks. And to be fair, I
wouldn't be shocked if you know that
July 7th deadline where Fable is going
to cut off on you. Would be kind of
interesting to see OpenAI turn on their
model for everybody on that date. Like,
come on. That sounds like a very OpenAI
thing to do, doesn't it? Now, while
we're on the topic of Open AI, I want to
talk about something really, really
quickly that's in the same vein, but
it's also something I don't quite know
how I feel about. Apparently, Open AI
has been floating the idea of giving the
Trump administration a 5% cut of the AI
boom, or basically saying, "Hey, we'll
give you 5% of Open AI." OpenAI has
floated giving the US government a 5%
ownership stake as a way of easing
tension with the Trump administration
and blunting mounting public backlash
against AI. Sam argued that giving the
public a financial interest in the
company would be the best way to share
the upside of AI. That 5% would
represent roughly 42.6 billion. Okay, so
here's why I have sort of mixed feelings
about this one. And I guess mixed
feelings isn't even the right way to put
it. This actually feels off to me. So
these AI companies, they need to get
regulated by the government so that the
models don't become harmful, but they
also need the regulations to not sort of
slow down their business interests like
what we've been seeing with 5.6 and
Fable. But if the government has a stake
in the company that the government is
also in charge of trying to regulate,
doesn't that create some pretty massive
conflicts of interest? Because now the
government stands to make more money
based on the success of these AI
companies which would then sort of
incentivize them to let some of the
regulatory hurdles slide so that models
can get pushed out faster so that the
government could make more money off of
them. Like how's that going to work? And
also the way this article was worded is
the Trump administration. Shouldn't it
be like they're giving it to the
government so the government could give
it back to the people? I don't know. It
all feels very odd to me and uh yeah,
I'll just get back to sharing other AI
news, but this was very interesting and
weird to me because I don't know how
this plays out. But let's talk about
another new AI model that came out this
week, and that's Claude Sonnet 5. Now,
typically when a brand new Open AAI
model or a brand new anthropic model or
a brand new Google model comes out, it's
typically the biggest news story of the
week. But this one's been totally
overshadowed by everything else we just
talked about. Fable getting shut down,
Fable getting brought back, GPT 5.6
getting announced but not released. And
it doesn't even feel like anthropic
cares that much about Sonnet. Like
here's the benchmarks. Agentic coding,
Sonnet still less than Opus.
Multi-disiplinary reasoning still less
than Opus. Computer use still less than
Opus. And knowledge work slightly
improved over Opus. Apparently, it's got
a lower rate of undesirable behaviors
than Sonnet 4.6. The main benefit of
Sonnet is that it's going to be cheaper
to use than Opus and Fable, but it's not
going to be as good as either one. But
if you need a model that's less than
those and almost as good as those, then
that's where Sonic comes into the mix.
Even on anthropic system card, literally
on page two, it says Sonet 5 is our most
capable Sonic class model, but it is not
advancer capability frontier compared to
more capable Opus or Mythos class
models. You don't even have to get too
deep into their system card for them to
be going, "Yeah, it's a new model, but
it's not as good as their other models."
But again, the cost is where it really
matters. If you're using the API and not
using like a pro subscription, you can
see Fable's $10 input, $50 output for
your tokens with the API. Opus is $5 in,
$25 out, so half the cost of Fable. And
Sonnet 5 is $2 in and $10 out. So, you
know, two-fifths the cost, not even half
the cost to jump to Sonnet. But that's
only through August 31st. The price
jumps to $3. So, three fifths and $15
input after September 1st. But again, if
you're using like a Claude subscription,
you're probably just going to still use
Opus. But I also know what you're
wondering from here. How does it do on
beautybench? Well, you probably already
saw, but let's look again. This is what
Sonnet 5 did on beauty bench. In my
opinion, Fugu Ultra does better. And I
think even, you know, Quinn 3.7 here and
Gemini 3.5 flash here do a better job.
But yeah, there's your Claude Sonnet 5
beauty. We also got some updates out of
Google this week. They released a new
version of Nano Banana called Nano
Banana 2 Light. And they also released
Gemini Omni Flash, so a faster probably
not quite as high quality version of
Gemini Omni for video generation and
editing. So Nano Banana 2 Light is
basically Nano Banana 2, just way faster
and cheaper. It generates image outputs
in 4 seconds and it cost about three and
a half cents per 1,000 images. So
really, really cheap to generate tons
and tons of images. Now, it does say
it's coming to the consumer platforms
like AI mode and search, Gemini apps,
notebook LM, Google Photos, etc. If I
jump over to my Gemini account, I do
appear to have access to it. I'll just
do a wolf howling at the moon and it
took about 6 seconds and it's pretty
solid. Now, keep in mind I am on an
ultra plan, so I'm not 100% sure if it's
rolled out for everybody just yet. A
monkey on roller skates, Gary Buucy's
face, a sign in a store window with
three products, their description, and
their price. This one I feel like took
like maybe 2 seconds longer. It took
about 8 seconds instead of six, but all
of them were really, really fast. And
then we have Gemini Omni Flash. Now,
this is one that I've had access to and
I've even made a video about it back
during Google IO, but it looks like now
it is rolling out to developers via the
API and Google AI Studio and it costs 10
cents per second of video output. If we
head over to Google AI Studio over on
the right, we make sure that we are on
video Gemini Omni Flash Preview. Again,
this is not necessarily free to use. So,
if you have like payment details on file
so that you can use the API, you should
be able to test this. I'm actually going
to take this video that I recorded at
Google IO looks like this.
And we will toss this in right here and
I'll say make Godzilla enter the scene
and start stomping around. And well,
I've tried multiple times to get it to
work and it keeps giving me an internal
server error. I thought maybe it
wouldn't do it because it was Godzilla.
So, I just said make it nighttime and it
still wouldn't generate. So, I don't
know, maybe it's having some issues at
the exact time of this recording.
However, I do have access to Omni inside
of Gemini. I don't know again if it's
just because I'm on the Ultra plan or if
it is rolled out in Gemini now, but
let's see if it works here. And yeah, I
got it to work in Gemini. So, let's take
a peek at our new video.
We got two Godzillaas. We got one in the
background and one in the foreground.
But you get an idea of what you can do
with Omni. It's really good at taking
existing videos and then sort of
altering those videos. It can also
generate videos, but if I'm being
honest, I don't feel like it's quite as
good at generating from scratch as
something like Seed Dance or even the VO
models, but it's okay at that as well.
And one last cool feature that Google
rolled out inside of Notebook LM, you
can actually create short form videos in
Notebook LM now that are like 60-second
vertical videos. So, if I go to my
Notebook LM account here and I go to my
birds aren't real notebook, which I've
played with quite a few times in past
videos, you can see we've got try new
short video overviews. So, you can
either try it here or I can just click
on video overview and select short as my
option. We'll go ahead and generate
this. This thing better be worth it.
It's been generating for like a half
hour. Okay, it's finally ready. So,
let's see what we got here.
>> Why do people increasingly mistake
obvious satire for actual facts? It's
due to a mental shortcut called the
bandwagon heristic. Social media
algorithms trigger this glitch to
actively hack your ability to recognize
a joke. Take a ridiculous spoof headline
like a politician proposing mandatory
vasctomies. Normally, extreme absurdity
acts as a natural defense mechanism.
That ridiculousness acts as a cue,
signaling your brain to reject the claim
as a joke. For how long that took, that
was not worth it. I mean, the audio was
kind of interesting, but the videos were
very, very, very basic, especially since
it took like at least 30, 35 minutes. I
literally walked away and had to come
back. It was taking so long. But anyway,
you can make shorts now in Notebook LM.
All right, I know I've covered a lot and
sort of rambled and ranted quite a bit
in this one. But I have a handful more
things that I want to share that came
out this week, but I'll just run through
them quickly in a rapid fire.
Starting with a new platform that came
out of Enthropic called Claude Science,
which is an AI workbench for scientists.
So, this is like a new app sort of like
Claude Code or Claude Co-work, but it's
specifically designed for scientists
and, you know, scientific use cases. And
you can use this app if you're on one of
the paid plans. Just go to
claude.com/prouct/cloudscience
and you can download it on Mac or Linux
right now. I'm sure it'll be available
for Windows eventually, but since I'm
not really using Claude for scientific
research, I, you know, haven't
downloaded this or played with it
myself. If you're into coding with AI,
Cursor just got an iOS app. With the iOS
app, you can launch always on agents in
the cloud or control agents running on
your computer from your phone. I've
started to do this a lot with like the
Codeex app because I use Codex quite a
bit. and I will have codec projects
running on my computer, but I'll be
controlling them and checking in on them
from my phone while I'm like in the
other room or while I'm away from my
house. Pretty cool. So, you can do that
with cursor now as well. Also, news that
some coders would appreciate. X now
offers an MCP server to make it platform
easier for AI tools to use. So X already
had an API that developers could tap
into to pull real-time data from X, but
the MCP server just makes it a lot
easier and a lot simpler for you to like
get your agents and things like that
talking to the X platform. If you're on
one of Google's paid plans like the AI
Pro or Ultra subscribers, you can now
have Google take notes for you when
you're on Google Meet. So Gemini
transcribes the conversation and creates
meeting summaries with key action items.
The notes are automatically saved to
your Google Docs in Google Drive. And
after the meeting, you'll get an email
with the summary and action items. I
personally tend to use Granola for this
right now. The exact same thing, but now
it's going to be native directly inside
of Google Meet. Gemini Spark, which is
like Google's answer to OpenClaw, is now
available on the Mac OS launch, but only
for Ultra subscribers right now. So, I
happen to have an Ultra plan and I have
the Gemini app. So, if you're curious
what that looks like, you can open the
Gemini app, click on Spark here, click
use Spark for Mac, and now you can have
it control folders and do different
things on your computer for you. So, if
I was to add, for instance, my downloads
folder. This is my example I always use,
but let's go ahead and allow this. I
could tell it to organize the files in
my downloads folder into the already
created folders. So, my downloads folder
looks like this. It gets out of hand
quickly, but I do have folders already
created here. If I submit this, let's
move my folders back over here. We
should actually see it in real time
start to organize my downloads folder
for me. Let me just move this over here.
And yeah, I mean it didn't really do it
in real time or you saw it. It was just
like one fell swoop. It went boop and
everything just got put into the
folders. But it organized my downloads
folder for me. So now Spark can take
actions on your behalf just like if you
connected a folder in Codeex or Claude
Code or Cloud Co or if you were to ask
your OpenClaw or Hermes agent to do it
for you. Well, now Gemini Spark can do
it too in the Mac OS app. And finally,
OpenAI is teasing some new hardware for
codecs. We don't have much to go off of,
but we do know they have some sort of
hardware coming out. It looks like some
sort of macro pad where you can have
like pre-programmed keys. Like I
personally use my Stream Deck thing to
like switch stuff around. Like that's
how you see me like changing screens
while I'm on video and things like that.
I think it's going to be a macro pad
kind of like this, but specifically
designed for codecs. There's really no
other information about it other than
it's coming on July 15th. It's for
Codeex and we just got like a post on X
that teases it but doesn't really give
us any details about what it is. But I'm
a sucker for gadgets. I mean I think if
you look around my office that's like
pretty obvious that I buy all of the
gadgets. So, you know, I'm probably
going to get that one too. And since I'm
a fan of Codeex myself, it's my main
sort of go-to coding platform right now.
I'm sure it'll probably be pretty
useful. We'll see. I have no idea.
Anyway, that's what I got for you today.
There is so much happening in the AI
world every single week. It is literally
a full-time job to try to keep up with
the AI news. But that's what this
channel's for. I drink from the fire
hose all week. I consume it all. I get
overwhelmed trying to keep up with
everything that's going on so that I can
make one video every Friday that breaks
down everything you need to know about
what's happening in the AI world. I've
also been doing more tutorials and
exploration of actual good use cases for
some of these tools in between my Friday
news videos. So, if those two types of
videos interest you, maybe consider
liking this one and subscribing to this
channel and I'll make sure more stuff
like that shows up in your feed. I'm
like 25,000 people away from a million
and I'm really hoping to get there
within the next couple months. So, you
could definitely help me get there by
just pressing that one little button.
That'd be really cool. Sorry, I'll stop
begging now. But anyway, my real goal
here is to try to save you from
overwhelm and also show you some
practical real world use cases of a lot
of this stuff that's coming out. I do
record these videos on Thursdays and
then I go and publish them on Fridays.
So, if any new news came out like late
Thursday evening or on Friday, well,
they'll typically make the following
week's video. But again, that's what I
got for you. Hopefully, you learned
something. Hopefully, you found this
helpful. I really appreciate you. Thanks
for nerding out with me. And hopefully
I'll see you in the next one. Bye-bye.
Woohoo.
What is up P everybody?
And we're live. What a way to start the