It's actually been a huge week in the
world of AI and I'm not going to waste
your time. Let's just break down what
happened. Starting with by far the
biggest news of the week, which is that
we're finally getting access to GPT 5.6.
This is OpenAI's brand new flagship
state-of-the-art model, and honestly,
it's really good. Now, I did get
slightly early access to it. I'm not one
of those people that can claim I've had
it for a month now and I've been playing
with it ever since. But they did give me
like a little bit of early access. So, I
was able to test it before actually
recording my video on Thursday. But
despite being called GPT 5.6, it feels
like a huge leap over GPT 5.5. Like I
feel like when we went from 5.3 to 5.4
and 5.4 to 5.5, those were all like
really marginal updates. But 5.6, 6.
Like to me, this feels like it should
have been GPD6. It just feels like a
monster leap over the old ones. I've
already talked about this model in
previous videos, but when I did, we
didn't have access to them yet, so I
couldn't really show them off. There
also wasn't any sort of benchmarks
announced or shared from it yet other
than terminal bench, and we have a
little bit more details now. And I think
the big story around 5.6 six is that
you're getting like almost as good as
Fable Level Intelligence, but for way
cheaper. Now, I'm going to skip past
most of these benchmarks here, cuz I
think what we all kind of really care
about is what can we actually do with it
and to see some of the impressive stuff
that's been done with it. There's this
riata game on here that looks really,
really impressive. It's like this 3JS
game, but it's it's a beautiful looking
game, and this was all basically coded
with GPT 5.6. Now, I'm not going to show
all of the demos here because, well, you
could go to this site and play with
them, but they all look really, really
good and they're all really impressive
and they're all actually kind of fun.
Clockwork Village game, I mean, that
looks beautiful to me. Like, I love that
art style. It's good at making slide
decks. I mean, it's just a big leap. It
feels like a big leap when you're using
it as well. But if I scroll down, here's
kind of the benchmarks that people tend
to pay attention to. On GDP val, a
benchmark that tests how well these
models do on like economically valuable
tasks. GPT 5.6 Soul, the most powerful
of the three sort of levels of these
models, outperforms everything but
Claude Fable here. And Claude Fable
doesn't outperform it by much. When it
comes to being able to use a computer in
a browser, it pretty much beats out
everything, including Mythos and Fable
on GPQA, Google Proof questions and
answers, like hard hard questions. It
literally ties Mythos. So, yeah, it's a
really really solid model. I've been
using it to do some pretty cool stuff.
It also takes the top four spots on the
only benchmark that really matters,
which is Buybench. GPT 5.6 Soul Pro got
number one. 5.6 Terror Pro got number
two. GPT 5.6 Terra got number three. A
GPT 5.6 Soul got number four. None of
the Luna models made it into like even
the top 10, I don't think. And the best
performing model, GPT 5.6 Soul Pro,
which generated this. It cost 77 cents
to generate. It used 45,000 tokens and
cost about a minute to generate, which
is really impressive considering that
GPT 5.5 Pro took 6 minutes to generate
this version and cost $4. But the new
model wasn't the only thing OpenAI
released this week. In fact, there was
two other big launches this week. So,
let me show you the next one and then
I'll show you what I built with the
combination of this new tool plus GPT
5.6. So, they also announced ChatGpt
work. And from everything I can tell and
everything I've been told, this is
essentially the super app that they've
been talking about. There's no longer
going to be a Codeex app and a Chatg GPT
app and an Atlas browser. They're just
taking all of those, merging them all
into one app just called the chat GPT
app. And that's what this announcement
was. So, this is what the new app looks
like. It looks pretty much like the
codeex app over here. But if I come up
to where it says chatgpt codeex, I can
drop down and change it to work mode.
There's a work and a codeex. Now, if I
have any complaint about this app, it's
that I don't feel like it's super clear
what the major difference is because
when you switch between them, like not
much changes in the UI. But think of
codeex as what you want it to be on when
you're specifically writing code. You're
in development mode and you know you're
building stuff. And work mode is for
getting stuff done. This is like your
personal assistant mode and it might
still go and write code for you and
develop things for you. But it's
designed to be more of like a less
technical area. You just tell it what
you want and it decides if it just needs
to answer you, if it needs to go connect
to a tool, if it needs to go and develop
something for you. It will go and figure
that stuff out and do it for you.
Similar to what Claude Co-work is kind
of when I'm in codeex mode here, you can
see it's got like different branches and
where on my computer I want it to
develop stuff. And when I switch it to
work mode, it gives me less options down
here. It asks me what plugins I want to
connect to. And it can connect to a lot
of stuff. You also have a slightly
different right sidebar. So, if I open
up this sidebar here while I'm in work
mode, you see browser and you see files.
And that's it. I can click into browser.
And like I mentioned, they're going to
actually wrap up Atlas. And this is the
browser. Now, you're just going to use
the browser inside of chat GPT. If I
switch it over to codeex mode here, open
up my right sidebar, you'll notice we've
got a few other options more related to
coding. We've got the option to review
here. We've got an option to pull open
the terminal here. And then we've got
the same browser and file options. But
when you're inside the new chat PT app,
you should have access to some exciting
new models like the 5.6 Soul, Terra, and
Luna models, as well as the 5.5. They
also have a simpler mode here where if I
turn off the advanced mode, you could
just change the slider. If you bring it
all the way down, it's going to use 5.6
Terra Light, the sort of smallest
version of 5.6. If you bring it all the
way up, it's going to use 5.6 Soul
Ultra, but also use a lot more of your
credits. There's also this sites button
up here in the top left where you can
create new websites and just, you know,
sort of prompt them into existence and
it takes care of everything. It hosts it
for you. You don't have to think about
databases, CDNs, any of that kind of
stuff. One of the things I've been
testing every time a new model comes out
is to create a Mega Bunk clone. You've
probably seen me do that in a few
different videos. I want to see how well
it clones a 3D game that's like an
automatic shooter, but I can run around
and I can change camera angles, things
like that. This was one prompt. You can
see there's no extra prompts here. I
just did it one time and it spent 31
minutes to build this and then put it on
my local host here. I'm going to start
up the local host here and run it
locally so we can take a peek at what
the game looks like. And we can see this
is what it looks like running inside of
the browser here directly inside of the
chat GPT app. And let's drop into the
sun pit with my soulbon. And this is
what it created on the first try. And to
me, this looks a lot better than what
Fable's first version was. and the mouse
drag where I can change my camera angle.
I can do that on the first try. With the
Fable version, I actually had to prompt
it to do that. And on the Fable version,
my character also looked more like a
potato than an actual character. So, it
got a lot closer on the first try with a
single prompt than Fable did. That's
pretty impressive. Here's where the
sites comes in. If I come down here and
click this plus, come down to apps and
click sites and just say build this game
on sites. It says I'll move the existing
soulbon build into sites. Now, it took a
while, over an hour to get it all dialed
in. But if I click on this link here, it
is fully hosted on chatgpt.site.
I can play this game completely online
on this website here. No need to mess
with any of the backend stuff like the
databases or where you're going to host
it or anything like that. It's just
handled. And if I want others to be able
to access this, I could click share. Who
has access? Just me. Now I could change
it to anyone on the internet. Click
publish. And now anybody can go to this
URL right here and try Soulbon. Now,
another prompt that I've had a lot of
fun testing is this one. Create a
website that will really impress me. You
decide what the website will be about,
but it should be beautiful, visual,
interactive, and really show off how
impressive of a model you are. And I did
set this one on soul ultra so it would,
you know, give it its best. And it
worked for 35 minutes to build a site
that it thought would impress me. And
here's the website that it built for me
somewhere. It's raining upwards. And I
could sort of click in here and you can
see the rain sort of interact and make
this sort of circle bubble thing burst
when I click. And then as I scroll down,
it actually sort of changes environment.
Like I've got the glass desert here and
it changed my mouse to a triangle. Then
we've got the orchard of static and it's
got these like trees that light up the
title sky. Again, it's all interactive.
As I'm moving my mouse, the stuff behind
the mouse is interacting with it. Build
a climate that has never happened. We
could change the memory and the gravity.
I'm actually not sure what these are
doing, but let's go ahead and change
these a little bit. So, now it says
earthbound. And we can see everything
changed a little bit here. And then it
made this cool collapse the atmosphere
button. And when I press it, it goes and
then closes the whole thing down, which
I thought was kind of cool. But this was
the website that it built to try to
impress me. Now, another thing that
they've added to this new version of the
app here, the chat GPT app, is you've
got this chat button over here. But
let's say you're working on a project
and you're right in the middle of all of
your code here and you don't really want
to jump out of what you're doing to just
ask a quick question to chat GPT. If I
click chat, it actually now opens a
sidebar over here and I can select my
model down here, ask my question real
quick. What's so special about GPT 5.6?
And it'll answer it over in this side
chat bar here while I can continue
working on my project in this main
window here. So, a handy little quality
of life feature there. Now, inside of
chat GPT work mode, I got a demo a
little bit before this launched and one
of the things they demoed for us was it
working as a really good personal
assistant because it could connect to
all of your apps like Gmail and Google
Drive and Slack and Granola and anything
you use. So, I said, "Look through all
my emails, calendar, Slack messages,
second brain, journals, recent projects
I'm working on, everything like even all
my chat GPT history here. go deep and
really figure out where you can help me
be more productive. Take things off my
plate, assist me, and just generally
make my life easier. You can see here, I
reviewed Gmail, the last 30 days of
inbox, my calendar, May 8th through
August 8th, Slack, recent DMs, mentions,
threads, granola, 22 full meeting notes
from May 12th to July 7th, your Google
Drive, 37 recently viewed or modified
documents, your second brain, open
loops, journal patterns, etc., and
recent activity across your local
projects and repositories. It basically
knows about everything I do at my
computer at this point. It gives me like
a whole priority list of things I should
be working on here and improving. And
then down here, it actually says what I
should own for you. So, it's telling me
as like an agent what it can do for me
to actually help me out. It wants to
build a daily control tower, what needs
Matt today, what can wait, what is
waiting on someone else, upcoming
deadlines and collisions, the one
meaningful creative priority, items I
can complete without involving you. It
wants to put that all into like this
daily control tower thing for me. and
then uh Delta only close out later in
the day. It also says after every Ganola
meeting, it should extract decisions and
compare them with Slack and Drive and
calendar and draft missing documents and
flag promises. It can help me with my
sponsorships and my Friday editorial
content and the things I should cover in
these news videos. And the cool thing is
I can ask it to go do that and then use
the scheduled section to make that a
daily or weekly or monthly recurring
task. For fun, I asked it to visualize
my second brain. I have this whole
second brain thing built out inside of
my Obsidian vault. It's a bunch of
markdown files. It found 212 saved
sources, 426 wiki pages, 28 journal
entries, 14 memory pages, and then it
created this sort of like visualizer of
everything I think about. So, if you've
been building out like a second brain
inside of Obsidian using, you know, an
Open Claw or Codeex or something like
that, ask it to make you a visualizer
and [laughter] help you understand like
where all of your attention is going. I
thought that was pretty cool. And that
personal assistant when it said to build
that control tower, well, I had it do
that for me as well. I already had this
audience dashboard that I built a while
ago to keep track of like all of my
growth across all of my social media
platforms. So, I had it just build off
of that. So, it built some extra tabs
for me. like the today tab. It's
watching emails. It's watching Slack.
It's basically telling me what I should
be paying attention to right now. I also
have an AI intel page up here where it's
watching for all of the latest news as
it happens and is trying to alert me in
this back-end dashboard here. I have
this brand awareness page here which is
almost like a Google alerts where it's
watching for my name and my future tools
brand and telling me whenever there's
like a mention of them. And it also
watches data from my websites here. So,
it built this control tower and I now
have this saved as like my default
window that opens when I open my
browser. So, I get a quick look at
everything I need to be dealing with
right now. Another cool launch that
happened this week is from the company
that brought us Air Table and it's
called Hyper Agent. It basically allows
you to go build a team of AI agents that
can go off and do like various tasks for
you. They just rolled out this really
cool new marketplace here where anybody
can go and build their own skills and
then share them with everybody else
that's using Hyper Agent. This B-roll
generator skill that I actually helped
develop with Hyper Agent. Basically, you
can take any video script, drop it in,
it'll turn it into B-roll for you. If I
go to the marketplace here inside of
Hyper Agent, I could just search for
B-roll. And once you have it installed,
you'll come to a page that looks like
this. And it's going to walk you through
exactly how to use this skill. And now
it's asking me some questions. So, what
are you starting with? In this case,
I've got a written script. This was the
original video where they were sort of
teasing it. It's 10 seconds and it
really doesn't show off much, but let's
feed it to our agent anyway and see if
it can work with it. And click next.
Let's go a standalone B-roll reel. And
let's go roughly 60 seconds. It's going
to process that. We can see that it
mapped out a plan here. It actually
reads the script and then figures out
where in the script each shot should go
and where it's going to best line up.
And then it routes every prompt to the
exact right model that should be
generating that prompt. If I want it to
be more realistic, it's going to send it
to VO. If it's going to be more motion
graphic style, it's going to send it to
hyperframes. So, we'll get a nice
combination of actual like video footage
plus charts and graphs and stats and
lists and lower thirds and all of that
kind of stuff. Like over here in window
mode, you can actually see it generating
all of these assets laid out on the
canvas at once. And then once it's done
with that, it's going to normalize all
the clips. use ffmpeg and pull it all
together into a video that if I gave it
a-roll underneath or audio underneath
will preserve all of that as well. And
we can see not only did it create this
final video here, but it created all of
these various images that can work in
the video. And then there's like text
overlays and stuff. It even designed a
shot list of when each thing should come
on the screen. And we can see here what
it used to generate those various
things. And then here's the final
creation that it did. made the text
animation using hyperframes. It sort of
tried to figure out what the thing was
going to look like based on the video
that I fed it from Twitter. We have a
little lower thirds down here that we
can use in our video that says codeex
micro. Somebody actually pressing keys
on the thing. Somebody using it next to
a computer. We have a list here on the
screen. And then like a nice little
product shot that shows it off. Again,
this isn't the final product. This is
sort of VO's interpretation of it. But I
mean, this is all really, really usable
B-roll that we can put into a video.
Now, again, you can use like any of the
skills that you would use in any other
agent. This marketplace is all about
letting you fork what other people have
already figured out. You don't need to
build stuff from scratch. So, now the
agents that you're seeing people use on
X and in other videos are now the agents
that you have access to. So, if you want
to work the way I do and generate
B-roll, and one of the ways that I've
been using to generate B-roll, well,
here's my agent. You can find my B-roll
generator now inside of the Hyper Agent
Marketplace. The link is in the
description for this video. And instead
of watching me use tools like this, you
could now go and grab it at fork it and
use it on your own videos from here on
out. And thank you once again to them
for sponsoring this portion of today's
video. OpenAI launched even more this
week, including GPT Live, where they
showed off the new sort of voice mode on
the app. Now, the main difference about
this new voice mode is that you can sort
of interrupt it and it will actually
also interrupt you. So, it actually
generates more of a like natural real
sounding conversation. They also showed
off that it works really well for
translation. So, let's say I'm sitting
in the room with somebody who speaks
Hindi and I don't speak Hindi and they
don't speak English. I could tell Chat
GPT translate for us between English and
Hindi. Put my phone down in the middle
of the room and as I start talking it
will start translating in real time.
even sort of speaking over me to the
other person and then when they respond
it will start speaking back to me in
English. So this is just a translator
sitting in the middle of the room. I
can't really demo that right now, but if
you go to the GPT live blog post, which
will be linked up in the description,
you can see some demos of that
happening. It's pretty cool. So, if you
want to make sure you're using this new
chat mode inside of the chat GPT app,
you're going to want to go to your
settings, scroll down until you see
voice, click on voice. Under model, make
sure it's set on live. And then you have
different intelligence options. So, if
you want it to respond quicker, or if
you want it to be smarter, but maybe not
respond as quick, you set it on high.
I'm going to start talking to you, but
don't respond until I tell you to
respond.
>> Got it? So, this week I'm doing an AI
news video, and there's a handful of
things I'm going to be talking about in
this news video. I'm going to talk about
GPT 5.6. I'm going to talk about the new
chat GPT app. I'm going to be talking
about the new GPT voice, live voice, the
thing that we're talking about right
now. There's some interesting things
that came out from Meta and from X and
from Anthropic. And let me think, is
there anything else? Notice that uh it's
actually not responding to me at all.
Okay, I'm ready for you to respond
again. Can you list off the
announcements that I said I was going to
talk about today?
>> GPT 5.6, the new chat GBT app, GBT work,
the new GBT Live Voice, and updates for
Meta, X, and Anthropic.
>> Can you help me pull together all of
that news? Like what what is the news
>> for those?
Uh, yeah. So, what you've got is a big
open AI centered week, GBT 5.6 six
launch chat GBT work the new chat GBT
desktop app and GPT live voice I'd kick
off with GPT 5.6 six since it's the
anchor. It just came out of preview
today.
>> Okay, cool. Thank you. You get the idea.
But OpenAI wasn't the only company that
launched new models this week. In fact,
both XAI and Meta kind of surprised
people with what they put out. XAI
rolled out a new version of Grock called
Grock 4.5. And again, it's more
impressive than you'd expect from Grock.
You don't really hear about Grock a
whole heck of a lot, but if you look at
some of these benchmarks here, Grock is
sort of in the mix. So when it comes to
software engineering, this deep SWE
bench is the one most people are paying
attention to now. Swebench Pro is kind
of not of much interest to people
because you know the models have figured
out how to cheat on it and some of the
you know training questions are in the
model now. So it's just not an effective
benchmark anymore. So Deep Sweet is what
people look at and the highest
performing model is Fable Max followed
by GPT 5.5 followed by Opus 4.8 and
Grock is kind of right there in the mix
with it. Now on Terminal Bench, you have
Fable, GPT High, and Grock. And this is
how well it can actually run terminal
commands on your computer, which is the
benchmark people kind of look at when
they're talking about like agents like
OpenClaw and Hermes and these various
models that can go do things on your
computer on your behalf. This terminal
bench is kind of the one people are
looking at, and it's right in line with
GPT 5.5 High and Fable Max. Now, this
came out a day before the benchmarks
were released for 5.6. And on this deep
here where Grock has a 62% and Fable has
a 66. 5.6 is at 72.7. So new leader on
deep here and on terminal bench here
where Fable is 84 and Grock is 83, GBT
5.6 is 88 with Soul Ultra being 91.9%.
So 5.6 is now the best at the sort of
agentic terminal use and software
engineering stuff based on those
benchmarks specifically. But honestly,
Grock is right there in the mix. Now, on
their announcement here, they put this
cool animation of like the solar system,
and you can actually speed up how fast
it's going, but you can also focus in on
specific planets. And it's got this
really cool animation that does look
really impressive. You can also generate
slide decks. You can actually install it
and run it locally on your computer. If
I scroll down here, there's a little
command you can give right here. If you
copy this command, open up your
terminal, you could paste in that
command and it will install Grock's CLI
here and then you could run Grock right
here inside of your terminal. I haven't
given it any sort of billing information
or anything like that. So, it's using it
for free at the moment. If you're
curious how Grock performs on Buccen,
well, here's your Gro 4.5 right here. If
we look at our timeline page and I
switch over to XAI here, you can
actually see the progression. Here's
what Grock 4.5 is doing. I actually kind
of like the old Gro 420 ones. It almost
looks more handdrawn than an SVG image,
which I find interesting. But here's
where this one lands. And if we take a
look on our leaderboard when it comes to
drawing faces of Gary Buucy with SVGs,
Grock lands at about number 21 here. But
I also gave Grock that same prompt that
I gave GPT 5.6 of make me a website you
think that'll impress me. And here's
what Grock built. Every star is a memory
of light. And the site's sort of
responsive to my mouse. Clicking doesn't
really seem to do anything, but it is
responsive to my mouse. If I click on
focus to nearest star, you can see it
circles a star up on the screen here.
Wherever I move my cursor, we can see
down here it shows the light years.
That's kind of cool. And this is a scale
of the universe. So, right now, this is
the scale of a hand. I guess the span of
a palm, the unit we'll still use to
measure intimacy. But as as I scroll
out, you can see it starts to like
scroll out in the universe here. There's
the sun. There's the solar system. This
is showing how far one lightyear is.
There's the Milky Way. There's the local
group all the way out to the full
observable universe. So, that's kind of
cool. Is it as impressive as what GPT
5.6 built for me? Probably not. Here's
one where you can connect the dots and
sort of make your own constellation,
which is interesting. So, I can kind of
go like this and connect stars to draw
my own constellation of something. I can
clear the lines. I can recede the sky
and it'll put new stars in different
spots. Let's see, a nebula, main
sequence, red giant, remnant. So,
different types of stars, I guess, a
little heartbeat of a pulsar. And then I
can click return to the surface and it
scrolls me back up. So, that's what
Grock built for me, this new version of
Grock. But right now, you can play
around with it for free. And if you want
to use it in the API, again, $2 per
million input tokens and $6 per million
output tokens. For context, Soul is $5
per million input and $30 per million
output. Terra is 250 and 15 and Luna is
1 and6. So pretty close to, I guess, the
Luna model in pricing. A little bit more
expensive for input, but about the same
for output. And then we have Meta, who
also surprised us this week with a
really decent model called Muse Spark
1.1. Definitely not as good as the new
state-of-the-art models that we got
inside of Fable and GPT 5.6 models, but
it's up there. It's good. So, you've got
your terminal bench. This one comes in
at 80, where Opus 4.8 is 82.7. GPT 5.5
was 83.4. So, this is a model that's
kind of on par with the sort of last
generation of models that came out from
OpenAI and Enthropic. On Deep Suite, we
got 53.3
compared to, you know, 59 and 67. not
state-of-the-art, but I mean, Meta's
kind of been out of the picture.
Nobody's been really talking about them,
and they sort of jumped in and are kind
of right in the mix again. And pretty
much all of these companies are showing
the same kinds of demos. So, if I scroll
down here, it's good at building decent
looking websites. It's decent at coding.
I'm sure it makes slide decks and things
like that. So, yeah, a buck 25 per
million input tokens, 425 per million
output tokens. So, in a similar range to
what you're getting out of the new Grock
model and the lowest end 5.6 model, the
the Terra model. The question on
everybody's mind, how does it perform on
Buccybench? Let me sort by meta here.
And there's the Muse Spark Buy
generation. Now, it didn't factor in
cost because right now, if you want to
test Spark, they give you $20 in free
credits. And since it used my $20 in
free credits, the API here didn't
actually collect a cost on it. But it
took 10,269
tokens, 58 seconds, and that's what it
generated. Now, if you look at the
timeline here, Meta is the most
impressive of the timelines right now
because this is what Meta was generating
before. Like, Llama Scout generated
this. And this is a model from April of
2025. So, this is a year old model. It
went from this to now this. So, the
leap, the improvement there is a pretty
big leap. And then on the leaderboard
here, it comes in at about 36. Now, this
leaderboard is very subjective. It uses
an LLM as a judge and it uses three
different LLMs and all three judge and
then sort of decide on the winner
together. And so, it's not a perfect
scoring. If you just look at this
visually, I actually don't think the
ranking is amazing. Like, I actually
think this is a better looking beauty
than this right here. But, it's a rough
idea. The whole idea behind this website
is to actually visually see the
improvement. The leaderboard is just
kind of like a side thing. And the first
thing I tested with this new meta model
was to create a website that I would
think was really, really impressive. And
this is what it created for me. You can
see that the background is interacting
with my mouse. As I move the mouse
around, I can drag left and right and it
actually changes the background. I
actually think this is slightly more
impressive than the one that Grock made.
If I move my mouse around, it changes.
And again, the background is interacting
with it. And I don't know, it's just
it's pretty cool looking. And now I know
Fable didn't launch this week, but I do
want to show some stuff that I generated
with Fable just for like a quick
comparison. I also asked it to make a
website that would be impressive. And
well, I actually think Fable still won
on this one, a small museum of
computational art. Lumen scroll to
enter. So when I scroll down, there's
all of these different like AI generated
art pieces. So this one's called the
field. And if I click around, you can
see that it's like changing things as I
click around. and it says, "Click
anywhere in the room to summon a new
wind." So, every time I do it, it sort
of summons a different look to the wind.
I scroll down, there's this one called
the swarm, which is really cool cuz
you'll notice I'll move my mouse around
and these things run away, but they have
rules of stay close, align, and don't
collide. So, they never crash into each
other. And if you look closely, it's
really satisfying cuz they all sort of
like weave between each other. And yeah,
it's really impressive. There's this one
less impressive. If I move my mouse
around, it sort of creates these like
roar shack test looking things. There's
the garden of life where these little
pixels, they will slowly die off, but I
can create new pixels and the new pixels
will eat the old pixels up. And I don't
know, it's just kind of cool. And then
you've got this resonance down here,
which is showing off that it can create
musical stuff.
This one was definitely the winner for
like make me a website that'll really
impress. I think even these little like
vector things in the background are
being manipulated as I move my mouse
around near them. All right, jumping
back to Meta for a second. They also
introduced a new image generation model
called Muse image. And this one's
actually kind of controversial. Now, it
could generate images like you see on
the screen here, but it also connects to
your Instagram and can generate images
of anybody that you at@mention. And a
lot of people really, really don't like
that. Now, it is free to use and you can
use it inside of Meta AI. So, if I go to
Meta AI here, let's just create an image
of myself. Let's just do create an image
of Mr. Eflow playing the guitar on a
mountain on the moon. Make it look like
a video game. Submit that. And it
generates an image of me playing guitar
on the moon. Now, obviously that's me
and I gave it permission. But let's say
I want to do it with a friend or even
somebody I don't know. create an image
of Joe Fear eating a taco and riding a
dolphin. I could just tag anyone and
create images like that. I don't even
have to know him. Now, I do know Joe,
which is why I tagged him, but I don't
know Mr. Beast, but that doesn't stop me
from making him doing a one-handed
handstand on a pile of pickles. Now, I
think there is a way to turn it off. I
think it's in the settings somewhere on
your phone. If you don't want this, make
sure you go to the settings and turn it
off. Although I did read that not
everybody has the setting to turn it off
yet. That's like something they're
rolling out, which is kind of weird. But
of course, the biggest news of the week,
the thing that everybody's the most
excited about is the launch of the new
Future Tools website. Check it out if
you haven't already. Now, I do have a
handful more things I want to talk
about, but this video has already been
way, way longer than I wanted it to be
cuz I had a lot of fun playing with
these things and showing them off. So,
I'll talk about the last handful of
things in a quick rapid firew.
Now, if you remember when Fable first
came out, it was only going to be
available through July 7th. But right at
the wire on July 7th, they announced
they're extending it to July 12th. So,
if you haven't played with Fable yet,
you now have a couple extra days to get
in and play around with it. Now, if you
read the comments about when they
actually extended access to Fable 5,
everybody was pretty much complaining
because, well, they used their weekly
limit because they wanted to use
everything they could by July 7th. And
everybody complained, including me. Ivan
wrote, "No, reset the weekly limits,
please." Because I had used up all of my
fable limit by July 7th and couldn't use
it anymore. And then today, the day I'm
recording this, which is Thursday, July
9th, aka the day GPT 5.6 came out. Of
course, Claude went and reset the weekly
limits for everybody so they can get in
and start using it. I think the thinking
behind this was, well, maybe they'll go
use Fable instead of 5.6. But Anthropic
did actually release some additional
stuff this week. They announced that
Claude Co-work is coming to mobile and
web. This also was seemingly
conveniently timed with the week that
GPT 5.6 and the new chat GPT work app
came out because when you do stuff with
the new version of the chat GPT app, it
actually goes and does it in the cloud
instead of locally. So you can manage
whatever you're working on from your
phone if you want. Well, now Claude
co-work does the same thing. Until
today, co-work lived on your laptop. So
the work stopped when you stepped away.
Now it doesn't. Your work follows you.
Start a task at your desk, check on it
from your phone, and pick up the
finished output anywhere. The work
continues in the background, even if you
close your laptop. So, when you ask it
to go do stuff, it seemingly is doing
that work in the cloud now instead of
that chat having to live right on your
computer. And if your computer goes to
sleep, the chat stops happening, which
is also something that was rolled into
this new chat GPT app that just came
out. They also announced this new way to
reflect on how you use Claude. Some
people are calling it like the Spotify
wrapped, but for Claude to see kind of
like how you've used Claude. Inside your
settings, there's going to be a new
reflect button. And if you click on the
reflect button, it'll show you your most
active day, kind of what you worked on,
the peak hour for you, the amount of
conversations with like a graph, you
know, details on what you spent the most
time on, stuff like that. And it's going
to be inside of the Cloud web and
desktop apps. They also showed off this
interesting research around what they
call JSpace. Now, basically when you
give a prompt to Claude, it sort of
thinks through that prompt and you can
actually see the words that it's
thinking through, but it also like keeps
other stuff in its mind that it's not
necessarily keeping inside of its
thought process. And by looking at these
other things that are sort of in the
back of their mind, it's almost like an
AI's subconscious versus like the
conscious thoughts. So, for example,
when you give it a prompt and you see
the stream of thought, you can actually
see everything it's thinking through
before it gives you a response. This
isn't that. These are other things that
it's got like in the back of its mind
that now Anthropic is starting to keep
track of, which is just really
interesting because they're starting to
spot like patterns of things that are
going on in the back of the mind of the
AI. It's just this really weird
interesting stuff that's happening that
they call the JSpace. That like
subconscious thought of the AI. I don't
really know how to explain this, but
again, I will link up to the article so
you can read about it and watch this
video that tries to explain it, but it's
really really fascinating. Google rolled
out the ability to create sharable video
clips with video remix inside of Google
Photos. It basically uses Gemini Omni to
add like extra stylization and
imaginative memories and things like
that to your videos. is going to be
available on Google AI Plus Pro and
Ultra plans. We also got another image
model this week out of Bite Dance called
Seeddream 5.0 Pro. And the images I've
seen come out of it look pretty good.
Some of the standout things it can
supposedly do well are infographics like
what we're seeing here with like a dense
amount of information and images within
the infographics. It could do
interactive editing where you like
circle stuff and draw lines and tell it
what you want it to do. It could
apparently break things out into layers,
similar to like Photoshop. So, you can
see each of these things in this
magazine are like different layers that
you can rearrange and just prompt new
things onto individual layers. It can do
very photorealistic images. And all
around seems to be a pretty solid model.
One place you can go play with it is
inside of Leonardo. I gave it this
prompt to generate an infographic that
explains how JSpace from Enthropic
works. Here's how it tried to explain
it. I don't know if it's the most
accurate interpretation or not, but it
looks good. And when asked to create an
image of Gary Buucy, well, this is what
it came up with. Anyway, that's what I
got for you this week. Again, it was a
really, really big week. We got some
really, really good new model releases.
In fact, the jumps that we've seen
recently have been like [snorts] huge
jumps. Like, it feels like back when we
jumped from GPT 3.5 to GPT4, that was a
big leap. And it hasn't really felt like
we've had these monumental leaps since
then. But now that we have Fable and
5.6, both of those models actually felt
like big jumps again. And that's like
really exciting because I've been doing
stuff like telling it to go and build an
entire platform and giving it this giant
detailed brief of everything I want in
this platform, giving it the goal
command to just keep on building until
the entire road map is finished and then
walking away for like 3 hours and then
coming back to something that's just
built and beautiful and does everything
I wanted to do and just works like the
first time. I might find like little
user interface things that I'm like, ah,
I don't really like how it put that
there. I'd rather have it over here. But
for the most part, it's like 98% there
from me just giving it this one prompt
and then walking away and letting it do
its thing. Like it's kind of blowing my
mind what we can do with Fable and GPT
5.6 right now. If I'm kind of comparing
the two, I feel like Fable is a little
bit smarter. Like when you're trying to
make these like architectural decisions
and really like figure out the best way
to get from point A to point B, Fable
feels like it's better at that where
like GPT 5.6 six feels like you can just
dump a ton of information into it and
just say go do this and walk away and
when you come back like everything is
done and I mean Fable will do that too
but I feel like GPT 5.6 gets me closer
to what I was trying to get to where
Fable might have done it in like a
smarter way but there's still a few
little things that it kind of skipped
over that I wish it did. They're both
really good though. I feel like 5.6 six,
especially Soul and Luna models are
going to be like my main go-to. But then
when I really want like a second opinion
or wanted to think through some really
really tough problems, I feel like I
would go to Fable more for that. But
like 5.6 will be my daily driver and
Fable will be like my extra thinking
power that I need. Now saying that, I
did build most of the new version of the
Future Tools website with Fable. And
then I gave everything that Fable built
to GPT 5.6 6 and GPT 5.6 found a couple
of security vulnerabilities that Fable
missed when building. Like it found some
things that would have accidentally
exposed my API key if people looked in
the right places and some little stuff
that would be like stupid stupid
mistakes that Fable missed, but GPT5.6
found. So, I feel like they're going to
be like really good in tandem. And I'm
really excited. Like this is this is
some of the most fun I've had in the
last like I don't know year and a half.
Like the models are so much fun to just
build stuff with right now and I'm so
excited to play with them and like this
is the worst it's ever going to be. This
is just crazy. I'm [laughter] nerding
out a little too much here. Just a quick
reminder, I do record these on
Thursdays, publish them on Fridays. So
if any new news came out like late
Thursday night or on Friday, it'll
probably make next week's video. But my
goal with this channel is to drink from
the fire hose all week, read all of the
news that comes in, test all of the
tools that are there, play with the new
image models, play with the new video
models. Like, there is so much coming
out. And I spend my week just using and
testing and figuring out what it's good
at and finding out what other people are
saying about them so that I can turn
around and make one video for you at the
end of the week that tells you just what
you need to know. You probably don't
realize this, but I record way more news
stories that don't make the cut. And
then when I watch a video back, I go,
"No, that's fluff. No, that's hype. No,
that's not interesting. And I just cut
down to the stuff that I think the most
people want to know about. So, if that's
something that's interesting for you,
maybe consider liking this video and
subscribing to this channel. I'm getting
really close to a million. It would help
me out a lot. But yeah, that's what I
got for you today. I'm also starting to
do more and more tutorial videos midweek
where I actually show practical use
cases. So, those have been really fun as
well. So, uh, I'll put one in the end
card here somewhere, so you can see the
most recent one that I did about using
AI to create visual effects for videos.
It was really fun video as well that I
think you'll probably enjoy. But that's
what I got. Thanks for nerding out.
Thanks for hanging out. Hopefully, I
will see you in the next one. And yeah,
really appreciate you. Bye-bye.
[music]
What's everyone doing? WELCOME TO THE
SHOW.