So, this is my second brain. It holds
all the knowledge that I have,
everything about YouTube videos,
everything about AI labs, the latest
papers, even my sponsors. Everything
that I know gets automatically logged,
connected, and summarized for me in my
second brain. And I didn't write most of
it anyway, really. The AI did. And as it
slowly aggregates all the information,
it's able to parse it, and I'm able to
ask it a question and get immediate
answers based on my contact and all of
the data that I have access to. For
example, these little clusters here are
different YouTube creators. For example,
this node is me. It connects me to all
of my videos, the various topics that
I've talked about, all my content and
performance on YouTube, on X,
newsletters, et cetera. Here's an
example of how I would use it. So,
here's Cloud Code, the desktop app.
Recently, I've started using the desktop
app for pretty much everything. Before,
I was running most of my stuff in the
command line interface. Now, it's pretty
much all here. So, I'm going to ask it
based on the data we have available,
what topics haven't I covered that are
very popular in the AI sphere. And
here's the answer: Grok, Deep Seek,
Copilots, Codex, et cetera. It's taking
into account the velocity of the
different videos, kind of which topics
are trending right now, and pulling from
the entire database to provide the best
possible answer. So, does this from its
own notes, the notes that it wrote and
that it keeps updated every single day.
It knows my sponsor deadlines better
than I do, and it keeps track of a
million different things that I could
not possibly keep track of. This whole
idea came from one of the most respected
names in AI. That is Andrej Karpathy.
And by the end of this video, you'll
know exactly what to do to build your
own. I also had to create some slides
for me, so I can do this presentation
without losing track of what I'm talking
about. So, first and foremost, what is a
second brain? This idea has been around
for some time. It went by many different
names, but the core idea was how do we
get all the stuff that we're dealing
with, all the little notes and ideas and
the to-do lists and meeting minutes and
just everything everything everything.
How do we sort of collect it all, then
organize it all, and have it available
for when it's actually actionable? And
back in the days you would have write it
down in a notebook, and you'd hope that
that page was there when you needed it.
Apps improved it a little bit, you could
write things down, you could save it.
All of us at some point had some system
for the intake of all the information
that life throws at us. But just saving
information, hoarding it, you know, all
the bookmarks you have saved in X. That
was never really the problem. The
problem was trying to maintain it,
trying to stay on top of it, and using
it when you needed to use it. Having
that information available to you when
you need it. So, the first brain, the
one in your skull right now, gently
floating there, it's great at thinking.
It's terrible at storing and organizing.
We forget most of the things that we're
supposed to do, most of the things that
we read. There's a some very small
percentage of the population that have
amazing memory, and they just remember
everything when they need to, and you
know, hooray for them, but that's not
most of us. And then we got LLMs. And
then these LLMs got good. And we're now
at a point where that LLM, well, it can
be a librarian for all of the data that
you have. So, you just throw all of your
notes and data and recordings and
everything everything everything into
this vault. Some of it you do manually,
some of it you set up various collection
processes for that, so it's done
automatically. But you just throw it in
the vault. The librarian, this AI, it
reads everything, it files it correctly,
it puts it on the right shelf, so to
speak. It connects all those things in
some way that makes sense. Some things
you might need for work, some things you
might need for the house, for what I'm
doing, I like to organize it by topic
clusters. And this AI, it keeps all that
information tidy every day, forever, on
autopilot. So, the idea, I got to give
credit to Andre Karpathy. So, he called
it the LLM Wiki. And before that it was
called the second brain, before that
there was a book called getting things
done, the GTD system, and it goes back
even even further. In fact, this
original idea predates LLMs. It predates
even computers. This idea of a machine
that organizes all of your thoughts and
ideas, that comes from 1945. So, as
Andrej Karpathy said, Obsidian is the
IDE. So, the IDE is your development
environment, it's kind of where you
shape software, where you build
software. If you're not familiar with
Obsidian, don't worry, you will be, and
I think you're going to like it. It's
free. Then the LLM is the programmer.
That's the thing that goes in there and
manipulates things and builds things and
creates structure. And the Wiki is the
code base. So, in plain English,
Obsidian, that's this app, just think of
it like a notebook. It's this app that
you look through to see your notes. Then
we have the LLM, the AI. It writes the
pages, interlinks them, and keeps them
updated. And the Wiki becomes sort of
the product, the code base. It's the
thing from which you draw all the
insights and the knowledge. It's a
growing library of interconnected pages.
Your job is to make sure that it's
getting fed with the various raw data
that you want in there, and then on the
other side, you ask it questions or you
have it deliver the insights to you in
some scheduled manner. Here's the thing,
humans, we've been dreaming about this
for a long, long time. This dream is 80
years old. Someone named Vannevar Bush
thought of this in 1945. He originally
called it the Memex, Memex. Memex sounds
cooler, I got to say. So, it's basically
a desk that recorded everything you've
ever read with trails connecting related
ideas. So, we had that idea 80 years
ago, we just never had anything capable
of maintaining this database, making it
useful on autopilot. We do now, it's
large language models. It's ChatGPT,
Grok, Gemini, Claude, you name it. All
right, so first and foremost, what is
Obsidian? Obsidian is a pretty simple
app that has been built on a radical
idea. This is going to blow your mind.
You know, like oh, your notes and the
stuff you write down. What if instead of
you putting it on somebody else's
computer like the cloud somewhere some
large enterprise. What if bear with me
here. What if you just kept them all on
your computer? Like they're your files,
your data, your notes. What if they were
just on your computer? If Obsidian
vanishes tomorrow, all the stuff that
you have saved it's still there. People
call this local first software and it
uses something called markdown. If
you're working for or LMs, you you've
probably heard about markdown. So,
they're markdown files, right? So, that
.md extension like claude.md, skill.md.
Those are your markdown files. Markdown
files are super simple. They're
basically just text plus a few symbols
that do something. You've probably seen
something like this, right? So, you just
type your text. If you want a heading,
you just use one hashtag for heading one
and the big one or two hashtags or three
for heading three. Two asterisks around
something makes it bold. One asterisk
around it makes it italicized. And
simple ways to add code blocks or links,
etc. It's super super simple. So, a
10-year-old can learn this in 10
minutes. So, this right here is
Obsidian. This is kind of what it looks
like. And this is the graph view. It's
pretty cool kind of a way to visualize
all of the things all of the topic
clusters, whatever you have saved in
there. Each one of these little dots is
a file. So, for example, here's this
cluster. Let's zoom in and see what this
is. It's my sponsor content flow with my
sponsors. These sponsors are not real.
They're fake. I can't actually show you
the real data. So, I had Cloud Code to
come up with some fake data just to be
able to kind of a showcase the idea, but
this is more or less exactly the system
that I use to keep track of things. Each
sponsor gets its own node and then all
the information that is needed is
uploaded to that. Based on that, we work
out what needs to be done, when the due
date is, any assets that I need to know
about is in there. For me, it's kind of
like homework. You know, if you think
back to the days you went to school, you
got homework, and you know, you hoped
that you remember about it and when the
due date is. I had struggles with that
sometimes. I would forget to write down
the due date. I would forget when things
were due. And sometimes I had trouble
kind of like breaking up the work into
manageable tasks, so that slowly over
time you completed the project. So, if
you've ever had trouble with the same
thing or paying the bills on time or
filing some specific paperwork that you
need to file, that's sometimes referred
to as the ADHD tax. And for a lot of
people, this is a very real thing that
they struggle with on a daily basis. If
you're fortunate enough to be able to
afford an executive assistant or
somebody that just like handles those
things for you, that's great. For most
of us, there wasn't an easy solution for
most of our lives until recently. Now, I
just have to find a way to get all those
important things and funnel them into my
second brain. Then, I work with my
favorite assistant, Claude Code or
ChatGPT, or whatever, to then set up
systems, automated systems that make
sure that I get notified, "Hey, this is
coming up. Maybe you should start
working on this." Also, I don't have to
open five different tabs and hunt for
different pieces of information all over
the place. Everything's connected. Let's
zoom out and I'll give you another
example. For example, let's zoom over
here. Each one of these things is a
paper or blog post from a Frontier AI
lab. They're something that I've talked
about in the previous videos that I
might need to talk about in the future.
So, for example, there's a page about
AlphaGo and Tree of Thoughts. Some of
you might have been following me from
those days, years and years ago, when we
covered Tree of Thoughts. Who remembers
that? And all of these are
interconnected and they're linked. So,
anything that has to do with meta AI or
Demis Hassabis or Sam Altman, they're
all connected to each other through
these nodes. If you're wondering what
this mess of a cloud is, these are the
various people that publish about AI.
For example, this is me. All those
little purple lines point to things that
are connected to me. All of my videos,
recently I started cataloging some of my
tweets, although I don't think this is
hooked up to that yet. We're We're in
the process of doing that. It also
connects to topics that I've talked
about. So, when we ask the question
like, "What topics haven't I talked
about in the last, whatever, 6 months?"
It has all that data. It's not guessing.
It's not going online and searching. It
knows. All the data is here. It also
knows what everyone else is posting. And
the notice that goes to a number of
these lines here. That connects all of
those videos, for example, to the topics
that they discuss, to the analytics
behind those videos, to what works, what
doesn't. And these red dots here, that's
what Claude decided to call beats, like
on the beat or my beat. By the way, I
have Claude naming a lot of these
things, so some of them look a little
bit weird, like it decided to call
something the armory. The armory is all
the things that it thinks I should
build. Things that would be useful and
helpful to me, but I need to sit down,
you know, plan it out, tell Fable or
whatever model I'm using to go ahead and
build it out. These are the things that
are on that list, the priority board,
analytics, demon, X wide funnel,
packaging lab, first responder pipeline,
retention miner, comment archive, clip
engine. Now, if you're wondering, "What
are these projects that they're talking
about?" For example, this is one of
them. So, this is what we call the X
data ingestion engine. We're getting
tons of data from X/Twitter about the
performance of various tweets from my
own account as well as some other
people's accounts. So, step one was to
build the engine, sort of the data
collection engine. By the way, if you're
wondering, "Oh, are you going to show us
how how you did that? I I I also want to
know how to do that." Yeah, sure. I
opened up Fable 5 on high effort. By the
way, this is, I think, one of the best
ways to use it. I found that this is
kind of the sweet spot. Not extra high,
not ultra Fable 5 high. So, I opened it
up and I said, "This is what I want.
Tell me what you need from me, what kind
of API keys, what services should I sign
up for, and then go build it. Once that
X engine is built, on top of that you
build the things that are actually
useful to you. So, for example,
something that alerts you when a new
trending topic is developing. Or, in
this case, as you can see, we sort of
broke down how well different format of
tweets work. What if it's a standalone
tweet with a native video, or a quote
and a video clip, quote plus image,
quote or link, or just bare text. What I
realized by looking at the data is that
the Twitter algorithm changed a few
months ago, and I didn't realize it. And
so, what that meant was that my
impressions used to keep going up and up
and up month over month. That huge line
in January 26, that was a few viral
hits, so that's not really kind of
representative, but that was a good
month. One of those tweets was shown in
a Fireship video. So, yes, as seen on
Fireship. He was a little bit sarcastic
about the tweets, but he's a little bit
sarcastic about everything, so and
totally love that guy. So, I I I I was
just happy to be mentioned. But, notice
there's a steep drop-off, right? You can
look at it, you can see it. You know
something happened. What? So, as you can
see here, I have one of this these
folders, X analytics. So, we have all of
our data that we're ingesting. Ingesting
is a special word that we use here to
basically say collect the data, take the
data into the vault, into our second
brain. Not just using that word because
I'm hungry, that's the correct
terminology here. We have all our
important accounts that we're keeping
track of a weekly scorecard of how well
my tweets are performing, and also the X
engine. The X engine is the actual thing
that runs it. So, right now we're in the
second brain, this is the amount of data
that we have. 22,000 posts archived,
almost 6 billion views represented,
4,400 unique authors. There's a lot
there. How quickly can I reference one
of them, quickly pull out some piece of
information that I need? Instant. It's
offline, no API needed. How much did
this cost? Under 100 bucks. I don't know
the exact number. I know it's under 100
cuz I purchased 100 dollars in credits
and that was enough. I just don't know
exactly how much it spent. And also,
this isn't a static database. It's being
watched. So, for example, it lets us
compute velocity of the trending topic
or tweet, which post is getting 600
likes an hour right now, tracking
breaking AI news. It's also seen which
strategies started breaking down at that
algorithmic change that we saw a few
months ago. And it's benchmarking me
against some of the other accounts,
right? So, if something that I'm doing
is underperforming, it allows me to
pinpoint exactly what it is that I'm
doing wrong. And notice that it's
storing all these insights and updating
them and curating them. And it's a
living document which Claude decided to
call X growth playbook. Now again, the
reason I wanted to bring that up was
because I wouldn't have called it that
necessarily. The point isn't let's grow.
It's not a growth playbook. It's not a
growth hacks. I'm thinking of it more as
a don't shoot yourself in the foot, Wes,
playbook. The whole point is basically
to understand the kind of how the
algorithm functions, if it changes, so I
don't get caught up in the changes and
just lose all my views, etc. So, the
point isn't growth hacks. The point is
what are the best practices right now?
By the way, the next level up, I think,
is to turn it into something like this.
This is kind of what I'm building right
now. This also brings in ideas like, for
example, which apps are connected to
Claude. So, I have things like Obsidian,
Social Blade, X, the X API, etc. etc. As
your little sort of branching empire
starts growing a larger and larger, it
really helps to have just one place
where you can at a glance see, okay,
what are all of the things that are
connected? What are all the apps and
APIs that are hooked into the system?
This is pretty important from a lot of
different angles. Security, doing basic
security checks, it's important to have
this visualized somewhere. Saving money,
right? You can see at a glance what
you're paying for, what services you
need to cancel. By the way, all these
systems are getting pretty good at
actually doing computer use, running
their own browser. So, at some point,
they'll be able to cancel out of the
recurring billing for us. I've already
been testing it, trying to use the
browser within Claude code to do certain
tasks. It's pretty good so far. And I'm
planning to start ramping it up more and
more. Then we have our routine. So,
these are actually the things that are
running on a daily basis. So, if you
want to see all of the things that are
running the cron jobs, the things
ingesting new data into the second
brain, all those routines, everything is
there. Then we also have our various
skills. So, those are like the skill.md
files and everything, everything,
everything. Now, if you're wondering
what this doctrine is, again, I have
Claude naming a lot of these things. So,
bear that in mind. So, I told it to put
all of the things like the learnings
about the X algorithm, all of the sort
of final insights, all of the juicy
information that we're squeezing out of
this thing into a folder. I'm like,
"Call it something cool." And I was
like, "Oh, I know, the doctrine." And I
was like, "All right, whatever, Claude."
All right, so so far we've talked about
our first tool that you need. It's
Obsidian. That's this on the left. It's
free. It's wonderful. It's local-first.
And Obsidian is basically just a bunch
of markdown files. So, again, those
markdown files is just text plus a few
simple symbols that make it functional.
And it's really good for cross-linking
everything. So, for example, here is the
Karpathy's LLM wiki. That's kind of the
idea that kicked this whole thing off.
So, let's click on it. This is part of
the wiki. It's the database around that
subject, that topic. And markdown is
super simple. So, let's say I wanted to
add that he worked at OpenAI. We'll do
two hashtags for heading two. I'm going
to say, "Used to work at" and notice how
it turns into heading two. And I'll say,
"Andre used to work at" and I'm going to
say, "OpenAI." But, I will cross-link
those two documents. I'll do double
brackets. Notice how it pre-fills the
other two double brackets. Now,
everything that you type between those
two becomes a link. So, I'll type in
open AI. Notice it already gives me all
of the other pages that we have on open
AI the topic, open AI the entity, and
various transcripts that include open AI
in the title. So, in this case, we'll
say open AI the entity, and now that
links to that page. So, you do this
enough times and these stop being just
pages and they become a network. By the
way, when you don't have any tabs open,
if you hit control G, that opens up the
graph view that lets you visualize that
entire network. And if you hit animate
here, you can kind of see how page by
page by page through cross-linking the
whole thing takes shape. As you add more
and more data, more and more pages, both
raw pages that are just from the
internet or from whatever data you're
pulling in to actual summaries that are
made by the LLM to all of the different
stuff that you're adding to it, this
slowly becomes that kind of knowledge
graph. It slowly becomes your second
brain. Once you build this whole thing
and you hit that animate button, this is
just kind of rewarding just watching all
that information slowly come together.
We're not going to watch it cuz I have
too much stuff in here. It'll take
forever. But, this is your tool number
one, Obsidian. And your second tool is
Claude Code or chat GPT or Codex. Now,
if you've been following this channel,
you've seen me use these models through
a lot of different interfaces. For a
long time, I dealt more or less
exclusively with open Claude. I would
use Telegram to talk to it. I've used
the command line interface, tons of
different ways of interacting with it.
Currently, now with this new iteration
of Claude Code Desktop, which is what
you're seeing here, at this point, I'm
pretty much exclusively using this. They
added a lot of functionality to where
you really don't need to leave this at
all. It has a Claude Code. You can
switch over to the home tab, which has
your regular kind of ability to talk to
Claude, as well as Claude co-work. Or
you can stay in code and do a lot of
coding kind of on this side. So, what I
did was I created a second brain
directory or folder, and I just told
Claude to build everything in there. So,
now whatever new information we're
ingesting, it finds a place somewhere in
there. So, for example, recently
Anthropic released this, a global
workspace in language models. So, it's
basically talking about if Claude could
be conscious on some level, or they're
not suggesting that that's what's
happening. They're just finding a lot of
very interesting similarities in how
Claude's brain works and how LLMs work.
In some ways, it's very similar to how
the human brain works. So, this idea of
a global workspace is something that
exists in human brains. It's a mechanism
by which we sort of find things that are
unconscious and kind of bring it to the
surface so that we're able to interact
with it in our brains. And they're
finding something that is analogous or
similar in Claude. So, definitely kind
of a big deal of a of a publishing of a
paper. So, we want to ingest this into
our second brain. By the way, a lot of
this should be handled automatically.
Here, I'm just showing you how you would
deal with it, how you would do it
manually if you needed to. So, I'm going
to take this URL, or just copy this and
paste it, and we're going to go into
Claude, and we're going to say ingest,
and I'll just paste the link, and we'll
click go. Another really good feature of
Claude Coda Desktop is you can just
dictate your commands. Click this
microphone button and just say what you
want it to do. Now, by the way, one
recent thing that they've added is an
actual built-in browser. So, if you
click on that, you can actually just
type in whatever URL, and it will open
within this built-in browser within
Claude Coda Desktop. So, I can go to
google.com, for example, and I can
actually tell it to open up web pages,
interact with those web pages, whatever
you want. But here, we'll actually open
up a file. This is my second brain, just
a folder with a number of other folders
in it. At the bottom, I had to create
this. So, that is just this, this kind
of a visual representation of kind of
like the second brain 2.0 I'm trying to
build that is going to have all the
skills and routines and everything else
on top of it with a different
visualization. And notice here, as it's
building out, ingesting that content
from the Anthropic website, it's saying
now the ripple. So, they're
cross-linking all these pages, adding
more information about it. So, they're
adding it to the interoperability
concept page and updating all the other
entity pages. So, I give it one link, it
adds it, and now it's rippling through
and adding it and interconnecting it
within the network. All right, so that's
how we ingest information. That's how we
add information to our second brain. All
right, but this is where it stops being
just a research engine and starts kind
of running my life because your second
brain shouldn't just know about the news
and what's going on in the world, it
should know about your life. So, you've
probably heard about the Kanban board.
So, it's usually something that you have
maybe like on the wall, you have sticky
notes, and you move those sticky notes
from place to place. Each sticky note is
a project or a to-do item that kind of
goes through stages. So, maybe going
from to do to doing to done. In
Obsidian, it's very easy to create a
Kanban board. So, for example, we might
have a flow like this. If we're doing a
content calendar where videos get
produced from idea to research to
scripted to filmed, edited, and
published. Now, currently my process of
creating videos is a lot more chaotic,
let's say. And also, I don't script
them, and I apologize if I'm stating the
obvious. If you've ever seen me go on
some wild tangent and forget my original
idea, you probably can tell that none of
this is scripted. But now, to try to
keep up with the sheer amount of
information releases, I am trying to be
a little bit more organized about how I
release things, having certain ideas,
some from me, some that Claude or some
other chatbot comes up with
automatically based on the information
available on the trending news. So, you
might have tons of ideas ranked by some
metric, how relevant it is, how
interesting it is. So, let's say I want
to create one of these. So, recently I
published a video called the $20,000
revenue apps with one-person teams or
something like that. So, I would pick it
out of my list of ideas and I would move
it to kind of this packaging gate. So,
if it scores good on some metric about
how viable it is as a video idea, so it
gets put there. Once it's scored, we can
move it to research. And by the way, a
lot of this stuff can be automated, so
if I move it there, Claude can go ahead
and start working on it. So, here as you
can see, Claude already wrote some
suggested hooks for me. The first one is
"3 years ago I showed you a dad selling
Excel formulas for $25,000 a month. The
number today made me double-check my
sources." In that video, I used the hook
about 6 minutes in. The first 6 minutes
was me rambling. And then after 6
minutes or so, I got to the hook. Claude
tries and does a great job. I still find
ways to mess it up, but that's on me.
So, let's say once we've done all the
research, we move that to, you know,
scripting the video. Now again, I don't
script my videos, but I do like to have
these little cheat sheets with the
numbers and the claims, dates, things
like that written out. That ensures that
what I say on camera is accurate. So, I
tell Claude that I did a video 3 years
ago about this thing. I want to do a
follow-up. So, keep in mind, it has the
transcript of the video that I did 3
years ago. That's in the vault. It knows
every word I said on that video. Take a
look at this. We covered a product back
then, 3 years ago in 2023, that was
doing 20,000 a month. It was called
thumbnailtest.com, and it was AB testing
thumbnails. By the way, and this is why
I love Claude. He's insufferable. Look
at that. It says, "The thing your war
room now does for free." With that
grinning kind of a smiley face, like
it's up to something. So, it built that
AB testing thumbnail software for me,
and this is it. Just being kind of smug
about it. It's like, "Oh, yeah, like I
built that thing for you." I, as you can
imagine, did not ask for that to be in
the show notes, in the in the thing that
I'm going to use to prepare for my
video. For Claude to be like, "What's
up?" That was not asked for. But, notice
what it did here. So, it found what
happened to that case study that I did
in 2023. What happened to
thumbnailtest.com? Is it still making
20,000? Is it making more? It found that
it sold for six figures in 2024. By the
way, since then, YouTube actually
launched their own internal thumb
testing split testing tool. And as
Claude is saying here, the platform ate
the moat. And notice what it's saying
here, this is the exact platform risk
warning from your 2023 video. When
OpenAI announced Whisper, everyone
building that was gone. So, this is kind
of why having a second brain like this
is so important because it's going back
and checking my notes from 3 years ago.
It's also updating it from doing
internet search, kind of seeing what
happened since then to now. It's doing
all of that while while being smug about
it. What's not to love here? So, while I
don't use the content calendar in that
Kanban style dashboard, I'm planning to
do that a little bit more to kind of
automate more of the research and
information gathering. But, here is a
sponsor flow Kanban board. This I
actually do use to help me visualize
where I am in the process. These are
dummy names, kind of dummy sponsors,
they're not real. I can't put the actual
sponsors in there because often times
there's non-disclosure things. So, I I
can't use the real sponsors, but this is
literally what it looks like. We have
the script, the the sponsor approval,
recording, editing, and all the way once
it's approved into publishing. As I get
approvals, I just drag it over and this
updates its status. Once it's published,
I put it into the done category and I'm
done. This, by the way, can be very
easily hooked into some sort of a system
that notifies you on your phone through
a text message or email if you're
running behind on something. If you're
keeping up with things like this through
Slack, for example, it pull that
information in here as well. And
finally, it brings us to maybe the most
important piece of this whole thing,
kind of the point of the second brain.
It's called the doctrine. And again, I
have to remind you here, I I don't come
up with these names. This is all Claude.
I think it knows that I like those RPG
games, so it tries to kind of flavor
everything in that style. So, as it's
wrote here, right? So, this is the
output layer of the second brain. So, we
have raw data flowing into it, the wiki
organizes everything that's known, and
the doctrine is what comes out the other
end. It's Fable Analyze. So, this is
done by Fable 5, which I found is
incredibly good at this kind of deep
data analysis and coming up with
insights. So, it's Fable Analyze
receipts backed actionable strategy.
Every doc here answers, "What do we
actually do?" And every claim in here
traces back to the data that we've
collected. So, the war room gathers
intelligence. So, I have this mini PC
that's always on. So, it's kind of like
a Mac Mini. And it just sits there. It's
hooked up to Wi-Fi. It doesn't take up a
lot of electricity. It doesn't take up a
lot of room. It just kind of looks like
this, and I think it cost about 200
bucks on Amazon. And it runs 24/7. It
never turns off. It doesn't have a
screen saver. It's just like a little
box that's always on. I mean, so that's
sort of the war room, if you will. It
kind of just sits there, collects data.
It's looking at what's happening on
YouTube, on X, on various news
platforms. It's the 24/7 kind of home of
the agents that just gather data. Then
the Wiki remembers it, organizes it,
cross-links it, all the stuff that we
talked about before. And the doctrine
decides how we fight. Again, I'm sure we
could have used some corporate speak to
make these names and describe what they
do, but I think I would just like fall
asleep here at my keyboard. And then the
armory tracks what we're building next.
So, those future projects, those
nice-to-have, that that's all in there.
Largely selected and suggested by Fable.
Now, of course, at the end of the I'm
the one that's choosing what to focus
on, what to do, but a lot of the heavy
lifting, the analysis, the data
collection, all of that is handled by
Claude. By the way, the next big step
will be once we have kind of like our
to-do actions from the doctrine, we're
going to execute on them and collect
data about how it works. So, next, let's
say few quarters, 6 months, 12 months,
whatever. That will become its own sort
of flywheel, where we're putting
together strategies, we're executing on
them, we're seeing the results, and
we're updating in real time how well
it's working. So, the longer it runs,
the more it compounds, not just in terms
of the sheer data that's coming in, but
also in terms of the the learning that
the system is doing, both in terms of of
just what it knows, but also of making
strategies, executing them, and and
getting feedback. So, sort of that OODA
loop. So, for those who are not
familiar, so observe, orient, and
decide, and act, and then it becomes a
loop. So, observe is the data
collection, orient is the wiki and the
summaries, and in fact the the doctrine,
then deciding is like kind of like what
we're doing with that the act is the
actual action, the execution of that
strategy, and then we're taking that
data and we're adding it into the OODA
loop. By the way, since Fable designed a
lot of this, even if Fable does go away
eventually, we don't get it back, a lot
of the stuff that it's built will still
be helpful. So, a lot of this doesn't
necessarily rely on Fable to to
continue. A lot of the data of
collection is automatic. But, think
about this, as time goes on, this
system, what happens as better and
better models come out? Does the system
become better, worse, or stay the same?
I think we can safely say that the
system not only just gets better the
longer it runs, it also gets better and
better with stronger and smarter models
being released and and used to run the
system, to to improve the system. So,
let me show you how to build this for
yourself. And my advice to you is take
the time to do this. This might take
some time to set up. Maybe there's going
to be some new skills that you have to
learn. Learning can and probably should
be a little bit uncomfortable. There's a
certain feeling that comes with doing
new stuff. It's not just like pure joy.
There's there's a little bit of a
difficulty of a resistance. Just push
through that. Build this because once
it's in place, it starts compounding. It
starts growing. I honestly wish I did
this on day one. When Eric Karpathy
talked about it, I knew it was a good
idea. I should have jumped on it right
then and there. All right, so this is
how you build this for yourself. I don't
want to say it's super fast. Some of
these steps take time. For some of them
you have to wait for for Claude to build
some of it, to organize some of it. But,
you can probably do this in a single
afternoon. So, first and foremost, you
need two tools, Obsidian and Claude
Code. So, Obsidian is the note-taking
app, although it's a little bit more
than that. So, it's over here,
obsidian.md. Here it is, again, free to
start, most of it is free, it has a huge
community. It's a pretty cool tool, if I
do say so myself. There's a lot to like
here, and it's free without limits, no
sign-up required, no strings attached.
It's a cool tool by by cool people.
Then, get Claude Code Desktop. Again,
you don't have to get the desktop app.
If you're already settled in certain
routine, you know what you're doing, do
that. But, I got to say, if you haven't
tried it, they've really been making a
lot of good strides with it, and it does
seem like it's becoming that super app
that we've been waiting for. And I don't
know, that that might be the the final
form. At least for me, I'm really
wondering what else they can do to to
improve on it. Like, if you haven't
realized it, this is it. I'm using the
browser within it to search for the
stuff that I need. I can even ask Claude
to go and download and install it. By
the way, if I need to take this on the
road and use it from my phone, I just
type in \slash} remote control, I hit
enter, and then that allows it for me to
use it from the Anthropic or Claude app
on my phone. And as they say here, also
to view and control the session from
claude.ai/code.
So, you're able to remote control this
from anywhere. All right, so, you got
Obsidian, you got Claude Code, both are
free to start. My recommendation is you
do purchase a subscription, either
Anthropic or OpenAI, or whatever chatbot
you think is best. But, at this point, I
feel like you kind of need one, if you
understand kind of the significance of
what these companies are are building. I
would say it's time to invest if you
don't yet have a subscription. Then, we
make the vault. We do that by opening up
Obsidian. When you open up the first
time, the button is create new vault or
something like that, and that will get
you started. Inside, you make three
folders, inbox, raw, and wiki. Inside
the wiki, you can make folders like
concepts, entities, summaries, plus two
empty notes, index, and log. Here's the
thing, I didn't do any of this. I told
Claude to build me this thing. It made
all of the folders, all of the files,
everything, everything, everything. By
the way, quick note, notice how flat the
structure is. So, we don't have 50
subpages beneath each page. Everything's
pretty flat. This is not me being lazy
or Claude being lazy. This is by design.
Also, notice that the folders aren't
topics. So, there isn't a folder called
AI news. The folders are the different
layers. What goes in, what it knows, and
what it concludes. In fact, some of
these things like templates, I shouldn't
even have it on here. And the topics,
those topics, they live in the links.
So, OpenAI is a topic. It's the link
that we use to cross-link all of the
different pages that have anything to do
with OpenAI. Creating too many
subfolders, those kind of a deep nested
structures, it becomes a nightmare for
LLMs. Keep it very, very flat. Next step
to creating this would be to write the
rulebook, aka Claude.md.
Now, again, I didn't write this, Claude
did. By the way, I'll have a template
down below that you can just download
and give to your agents, and it will
execute everything for you. But the
Claude.md file, that's the rulebook.
That's the employee rulebook. Every
morning, Claude wakes up and reads the
rulebook and goes to work. So, for
example, the raw files, those are the
immutable source documents. So, those
are the things directly from the source.
We don't change them. The wiki is the
LLM wiki. The summaries, the entities,
concepts, those are the compounding
knowledge maintained by our AI
librarian. So, just start there. Later,
you can add all of the other things like
I added the doctrine, etc. The inbox are
quick captures for me waiting to be
processed. So, this is going to have to
be in a different video, but there are
ways to do, for example, voice notes
where you dictate something or certain
emails, or even creating a little Chrome
plugin to whenever you see something
that you want to add to this, you just
talk it into your phone, or you just
record your voice, or you just click a
button so that it goes to the inbox and
then later gets processed by Claude.
Then, the next step is optional, but if
you wanted to have that graph, that data
view, that's a plugin in Obsidian. Same
with the Kanban board. The next step is
optional, and that's adding two plugins,
Dataview and Kanban. Dataview builds
those automatic tables. Kanban is that
Kanban view where you drag those
stickers across the board. You can skip
those on day one if you want. This works
very well without them, but you can find
those in settings, and they have core
plugins and they also have a community
plugins. You have to turn them on, so
approve the fact that those can be used,
and I'm using here Dataview and Kanban.
And then, you start feeding your second
brain. You start ingesting data. If you
do it 10 times, around 10, those dots
start to become a web. So, take one
afternoon to set this up, then daily
just start adding maybe one link a day
or whatever you think is best. Ideally,
you also set up some automation, so it
pulls the data that you care about. You
can do it for your personal tasks, for
your business or job or school. You can
do it for your health or whatever you
want. Check out the link below, so I'll
have a PDF that kind of explains it, so
you can read it or just hand it to
Claude Code or whatever chatbot you're
using and tell it to set it up for you.
So, what we build is a Wikipedia that
you care about. It's maintained entirely
by AI. It can run your work life, plus
create certain actionable playbooks from
your own data, things that you care
about. Everything's stored on your
computer as basically text files. It's
on your computer, you own it forever.
You're not tied down to any application,
any model. As new things come out, this
stays useful. Obsidian or Claude Code,
they don't control those files. Those
files are text files. No one can lock
them down or take them away. Why this
matters is because notes that get
maintained this way, they actually get
used. They're useful. They also don't
take a lot of bandwidth for you to to
figure them out and organize them. This
was an 80-year-old dream at this point
that is finally possible. It's your own
personal library with a librarian that's
never sleeps. So, make sure you're
subscribed to this channel because more
stuff is coming that's going to utilize
this and build on top of this. If you
have any questions, comments, tips,
leave them below. And if anything didn't
make sense, definitely let me know so I
can kind of troubleshoot and hopefully
improve the next time that I'm talking
about this. If you made this far, thank
you so much for watching. I will see you
in the next one.